翻译   伊森泽生 Eunice 青椒 王木木
翻译   克里斯 学术男优 子V 苏葵
校对   克里斯
时间轴   想念Gallifrey的Wholock 西·查 今 啾啾啾
后期   吉吉
总监   克里斯
科帕卡巴纳俱乐部
纽约城 1962年
纽约人民 你们好 我是鲍比·莱德尔
Hello New York! I'm Bobby Rydell.
我很高兴能来到这里
And I'm glad to be here.
谢谢大家今晚来看我们的演出
Thank you all for coming to see us tonight.
今天是科帕俱乐部的周六狂欢夜
It's Saturday night in the Copa!
我们认为你们今晚会玩得很开心
We think you're gonna have a great time tonight.
我们会竭尽全力确保你们玩得开心
We're gonna do our best to make sure of that.
一如既往 我们要特别感谢朱尔斯·波德尔先生
As always a very special thanks to Mr. Jules Podell
朱尔斯·波德尔
是科帕卡巴纳夜店的运营者
让我们有玩乐的可能
for having us out.
开始吧
Let's get started.
*我已经完全被那古老的黑魔法控制*
*That old black magic has me in its spell*
*就是你运用得如此娴熟的黑魔法*
*That old black magic that you weave so well*
*那冰冷的手指顺着我的脊柱上下探索*
*Those icy fingers up and down my spine*
*跟我们目光相接时你施展的巫术一样*
*The same old witchcraft when your eyes meet mine*
*令我着迷*
*I love them so well*
*跟我彼时内心感受到的微微刺痛感一样*
*The same old tingle that I feel inside*
*随后电梯开始上升*
*And then that elevator starts its ride*
*亲爱的...*
*And darling...*
你好啊 亲爱的
Hello sweetheart.
这是我的大衣
Here is my coat.
看到这顶帽子了吗
And you see this here hat?
我希望你用生命来守护它
I want you to guard it with your life.
这是我母亲送我的礼物
It was a gift from my mother.
遵命 劳斯库德先生
Yes, Mr. Loscudo.
这是赏你的
That's for you.
谢谢您 先生
Thank you sir.
吉奥
Gio!
- 卡迈因 你还好吗 - 很高兴见到你
- Carmine! How are you pal? - Good to see you.
谢谢 您完全不必如此的
Oh thank you! That's unnecessary.
来 我们走 去听音乐
Come on! Let's go. On the album.
我两年前在南费城见过那个叫鲍比·莱德尔的小子
I saw this kid Bobby Rydell two and a half years ago in South Philly.
当时他还是个无名之辈
Nobody knew who he was.
现在他可出名了
They know now.
把劳斯库德的帽子给我
Gimme Loscudo's hat.
但他叫我守...
But he said to guard it...
我知道 我听到了
I know, I heard.
给我 行吗
Give it to me. A'right?
*我应该远离你 但我能怎么办*
*I should stay away but what can I do*
*我听到你的名字...*
*I hear your name...*
放尊重点 嘴巴放干净点
Be respectful and watch your mouth.
闭嘴 是她卖弄风骚勾引我
Shut up! She wants it, Okay?
硬汉 你能怎么样
Tough guy, what are you gonna do?
托尼·利普
Tony Lip!
*你就是我一直在等待的爱人*
*You're the lover I have waited for*
*是我命中注定的爱侣*
*The mate that fate had me created for*
*每次我们亲吻时...*
*And every time you lips meet mine*
你竟敢对我动手 混蛋
You put your hands on me, you punk?
给自己留点面子 跟你朋友一起回家去吧
Do yourself a favor. Go home with your friends.
你无权命令我该去哪儿
You don't tell me where to go!
你知道我是谁吗  我非要进去
Do you know who I am?! I'm goin' back in there!
*那叫做爱情的古老黑魔法啊*
*That old black magic, yeah love*
你去告诉朱尔斯·波德尔
You tell Jules Lipobdell.
如果找不回我的帽子 我就把这家夜店烧了
If I don't get my hat I'm gonna burn this joint down.
吉奥 它肯定会再出现的
Gio, it's gonna turn up.
我发誓它一定会再次出现的
I swear to God it's gonna turn up.
是吗 你告诉那个犹太肥猪
Really? You tell that fat Jew bastard
如果拿不回帽子 我就把科帕俱乐部给烧了
I don't get my hat I'll burn Copa down!
科帕俱乐部 重新装修期间停业
我只能继续去开垃圾车谋生了
I'm gonna have to go back to driving garbage trucks.
老天呐
Jesus Christ!
妈的 他真是疯了
Screw those! He's out of his mind.
至少我们今晚挣到了钱
We earned our money tonight.
利普 我当时以为你要杀了那家伙
Lip, I thought you were gonna kill that guy.
是啊
Yeah!
他死总比我死要好
Better him than me.
那停业期间 你打算去做什么
So... What are you gonna do while we're closed?
我不知道 或许会去我叔叔的披萨店工作
I don't know. Maybe go work at my Uncle's pizza joint.
- 你呢 - 我要喝两个月的酒
- You? - I'm gonna drink for 2 months.
送我回家 利普
Take me home, Lip.
再见 卡迈因
See you, Carmine.
不 你不该那样 不应该发生这种事
No! You shouldn't. That shouldn't happen.
我不想当一个...
I don't wanna be a...
我的帽子
My hat!
我听说它丢了 于是我就找了找
Heard it was missing, so I looked into it.
- 我当时都想杀了那个小婊子 - 不 不是她的错
- I wanted to kill that broad. - No. No. Wasn't her fault.
是谁胆大包天 敢偷吉奥的帽子
Who had the balls to clip Gio's hat?
别担心 我已经解决他了
Don't worry about it, I took care of him.
很好 希望你把他好好打了一顿
Yeah! I hope you gave him some beating.
给 收下吧 放进钱包里
Here. Take this. Put it in your kick.
不 谢谢了 能帮忙是我的荣幸 劳斯库德先生
No. No thanks. It was a pleasure, Mr. Loscudo.
别废话了 收下吧
Bullshit! Take it.
从现在开始 别再叫我劳斯库德先生了
And from now on, you don't call me Mr. Loscude,
听到了吗
ya hear me?
我是你的好兄弟吉奥
I'm your pal Gio.
布朗克斯
纽约
白箭香烟
早安
Good morning.
晚安
Good night!
一名击球手出局 下一位是罗杰·马里斯
One down, and the batter will be Roger Maris.
加油啊 罗杰 击个好球
Come on, Roger! Hit one out!
约翰尼 闭嘴 你会给他招来霉运
Johnny quite! You're gonna jinx it.
约翰尼 你还能吼得更大声点吗
Johnny, think you can yell a little louder?
- 马里斯上场了 - 是啊 我也被吵起来了
- Maris is up. - Yeah, so am I now.
你们到这里来干什么
What the hell are you guys doing here?
我们是来陪德洛丽丝的
We came over to give Dolores company.
不是吧
Come on!
你别只顾着自己睡觉 让我女儿一个人
面对这些黑鬼
你明白我的意思吗
我事先也不知道他们会派谁上门来啊
我不知道他们会派黑鬼过来
这应该是意大利人的工作 真可耻
谢谢你 夫人
Thank you, ma'am.
投球了
Here's the pitch.
出界 飞向观众席
Fouls it back to the crowd.
一坏球 一好球
One ball, one strike.
加油啊 罗杰 拜托了
Come on Roger! Please!
- 我送你们出去 - 好的
- I'll walk you out. - Sure.
看来还得我们重回赛场了 拜托
We need to get back to this ball game. Come on!
- 非常感谢 - 如果有问题 给我们打个电话
- Thank you so much! - Any problems, give us a call.
- 两好球一坏球 - 加油
- The one- two pitch. - Come on, baby.
球径直飞进右外场深处
The curve is hit deep into right field...
赢了 赢了
We got it! We got it!
再来一次 再来一次 加油 宝贝
Do it again. Let's do it again. Come on baby!
别 托尼 快去穿衣服 我们要开饭了
No! Tony, go get dressed. We're gonna eat.
好吧
Alright!
没第七场了 不用打第七场了
No game seven. No game seven.
主啊 感谢您的慷慨 阿门
From thy bounty, through Christ our Lord, Amen.
阿门
Amen.
如果谁听闻有适合托尼的工作岗位 告诉我们一声
And if anyone hears of a job for Tony, let us know.
- 德洛 - 怎么了
- Dolor! - What?
别这样
Please.
- 发生什么事了 你被开除了吗 - 不是
- What happened? Did you get fired? - No.
不是 科帕俱乐部要停业装修
No, The Copa's closing for repairs.
所以他需要找一份为期几个月的短期工作
So he just needs something for a couple months.
谁叫你把自己当大亨了 就知道乱花钱
够了 爸 地板发霉腐烂了 我们不得不换
他人脉这么广 很快就能找到新工作的
All the people he knows, he'll find something in no time.
他之前在卫生部有份很好的工作
He had a great job at the sanitation department.
你不该揍那个领班的
You shouldn't have punched out the foreman.
他不该把我叫醒的
He shouldn't have woke me up.
确实是你的作风
That's Tony.
我跟你说
I'm tellin' you,
这将是你赚得最轻松的五十块
this is gonna be the easiest fifty bucks you ever gonna made.
好吧 再看吧
Yeah we'll see.
瞧瞧 他们来了
Hey! There they are.
你好 约翰尼
Hi, Johnny.
- 托尼 - 保罗 你还好吗
- Tony! - Hey Paulie. How you doing?
我很好 约翰尼跟我说
I'm good. I'm good. So, Johnny here tells me
你曾一口气吃了48个白城堡汉堡
you ate forty- eight White Castle burgers all in one sitting.
是芝士汉堡
Cheese burgers.
- 你来告诉他们 弗朗基 - 我不信
- You tell them, Frankie. - I don't believe you.
你信不信关我什么事
What do I care if you believe me?
戈曼
Gorman.
这里吃热狗的最高纪录是多少
What's the record here for Hotdogs?
18个 肥保罗的战绩
Eighteen. Fat Paulie.
利普怎么没参加这个比赛
Why wasn't Lip in on that contest?
什么比赛 我当时只是饿了而已
What contest? I was hungry.
赌局很简单 50美元
Bet's simple. Half a C- note.
- 比谁在一小时内吃的热狗最多 - 带顶层调料的
- Most hotdogs in an hour wins. - With toppings.
你体重多少
What the hell you weigh?
- 260磅 - 你的左半边屁股都有260磅了
- Two sixty. - Your left ass weighs two sixty.
如果我撒谎 就让我岳母立刻死亡
May my mother- in- law drop dead on the spot if I'm lyin'.
- 好吧 我应战 - 很好
- Alright. You're up. - Good.
加速啊 利普 那个象崽迟到第19个了
Pick it up Lip! The baby elephant just hit nineteen!
加油 利普 加油
Let's go Lip! Let's go. Come on.
你真丢人
You are embarrassing.
你让你儿子丢人了 他遥遥领先了
You're embarrassing your son. He's killing you.
- 尼基 你在做家庭作业吗 - 是的
- Nicky. You do your homework? - Yep.
很好
Good.
- 你去哪儿了 - 戈曼那里
- Where have you been? - Gorman's.
我在做晚餐
I'm making dinner!
肥保罗跟我打赌50块
Fat Paulie bet me fifty bucks
认为他能比我吃下更多的热狗
he could eat more hot dogs than me.
他吃了24个 那家伙简直是畜生
He knocked off twenty four. Guy's an animal.
你是疯了吗
Are you crazy?
你输了50美元吗
You lost fifty dollars?
德洛丽丝 拜托
Dolores. Please.
我吃了26个
I ate twenty six.
你真是太走运了
You're so lucky.
你知道吗
You know that?
周一就得交房租了
Rent is due on Monday.
你不接电话吗
You're gonna get that?
什么事
Yeah?
利普 有人打电话过来了
Lip. Some guy called over here,
是个医生 他在找一个司机
a doctor. He's looking for a driver.
- 你有兴趣吗 - 有
- You interested? - Yeah.
他们明天下午会举行面试
They're interviewing guys tomorrow afternoon.
地址是..
The address is...
第七大道881号 下午2点15分
Eight eighty one, 7th avenue, two fifteen.
卡内基大厅
- 不好意思 - 我们现在还未开业
- Excuse me. - We're not open right now.
但你可以购买今晚的演出票
But you're welcome to buy tickets to tonight's performance.
不 不是这么回事
Nah. That's not it.
我好像搞错地址了
I think I got the wrong address.
这里有医生的办公室吗
But is there a doctor's office in here?
医生办公室
A doctor's office?
谢利医生
Dr Shirley.
你的地址没错
You have the correct address.
谢利医生住在楼上 在大厅上面
Dr Shirley lives upstairs, above the hall.
你们好
How you doing?
我是来应聘司机职位的 托尼·利普
I'm here for the driver job. Tony Lip.
没有叫托尼·利普的
No Tony Lip.
不 名单上应该有才对
No, it should be on there.
没有
No.
我这倒是有个托尼·瓦...瓦莱...
I have a Tony Val... Valle...
瓦莱隆加 没错 就是我
Vallelonga. Yeah, that's me.
- 等候期间把这个填了 - 什么
- Fill it out while you wait. - What?
等候期间把这个填了
Fill it out while you wait.
坐吧
Have a seat.
瓦莱隆加先生 抱歉让你久等了
Mr. Vallelonga, sorry to keep you waiting.
我是唐纳德·谢利医生
I'm Dr. Donald Shirley.
- 叫我托尼吧 - 好的 请坐
- Tony. - Yes. Please sit down.
你这个地方真奢华啊
Some place you got in here.
那些角是真货吗
Them horns real?
是象牙 没错
Elephant tusks. Yes.
那个呢
What about that?
那是臼齿吗
That a molar?
- 什么 - 臼齿
- A what? - A molar.
鲨鱼牙齿吗
Like a Shark tooth?
可能是虎牙吧
Tiger's maybe.
是别人送的礼物
It was a gift.
我以为我是要来一个办公室呢
I thought, I thought I was going to a office.
他们跟我说有个医生需要一位司机
They said a doctor needed a driver.
他们就这么说的吗
That's all they told you?
- 是的 - 实际上 要比这复杂得多
- Yeah. - Actually, it's a bit more complicated than that.
你以前当过职业司机吗
Have you ever driven professionally before?
搞卫生的 开垃圾车
Sanitation. Garbage trucks.
并且我晚上会开车送我老板回家
Plus I drive my boss home at night.
但我什么车都会开
But I can drive anything.
豪华轿车 拖车
Limos, tow trucks.
铲雪车 什么都行
Snow palms, whatever.
我明白了 你还有其他什么经验
I see. What other experience do you have?
我在很多娱乐场所都工作过
I worked a lot of joints.
比如车轮酒吧 薄荷糖舞厅 科帕俱乐部
The Wagon Wheel, Peppermint Lounge, Copa
- 什么岗位 - 你什么意思
- In what capacity? - What do you mean?
你在这些地方负责做什么
What did you do there?
公关
Public relations.
首先 托尼
Well, first of all, Tony,
我不是医生 我是个音乐家
I'm not a medical doctor. I'm a musician.
- 歌曲那种吗 - 是的
- You mean like songs? - Yes.
我即将开启一段音乐会巡演
I'm about to embark on a concert tour,
大部分旅程都是南下
the majority of which will be down South.
- 大西洋城吗 - 不是
- Atlantic city? - No.
最南部 我们先从中西部开始
The deep south. First we're starting in the Midwest,
然后一路向左
but then we're taking a hard left.
去肯塔基 北卡罗来纳
Kentucky, North Carolina,
田纳西 穿越整个三角洲地区
Tennessee, and on down through the Delta.
预想一下 你觉得为黑人工作会不会有问题
Do you foresee any issues in working for a black man?
当然不会
No!
没问题 前几天我跟我妻子
No no. Just the other day me and the wife had
还邀请几个黑人来家里
a couple of colored guys over at the house.
喝东西
For drinks.
我知道了 你结婚了
I see, you're married.
没错 有两个孩子
Yeah. Two kids.
我不确定已婚男人是否适合这份工作
I am not sure this is the proper job for a married man.
为什么 要带上女人吗
Why, we bringing broads?
我是指 你要离家八周
My point is, you'll be gone for eight straight weeks,
中途没得休息 直到圣诞
no breaks, right up until Christmas.
你确定你能离开家人那么久吗
You're quite sure you can leave your family for that long?
那要看你给我多少钱了
Depends on what you're paying.
每周一百美元 包食宿
A hundred dollars a week, plus room and board.
但我要先说清楚 我不只是请一个司机
But let me be crystal clear... I'm not just hiring a chauffeur.
我要一个能处理我行程的人
I need someone who can handle my itinerary.
当我的私人助理 我需要一个侍者
Be a personal assistant. I need a valet.
一个能帮我洗衣 擦鞋的人
I need someone who can launder my clothes, shine my shoes...
祝你好运 医生
Good luck, Doc.
托尼
Tony.
我让我的唱片公司在城内打听 找合适的人选
I had my record label ask around town to find me the right man.
你的名字多次出现
Your name came up more than once.
你给一些人留下了深刻印象
You've impressed several people with your...
你具有解决麻烦的天赋
innate ability to handle trouble.
所以我才打电话问你能否来任职
And that is why I called and inquired about your availability.
这样行不 跟你一起出行没问题
OK, here is the deal. I got no problem being on a road with you.
但我可不是什么管家
But I ain't no butler.
我不会给人干熨衣服 擦鞋的事
I ain't ironing no shirts, and I'm not polishing nobody's shoes.
如果你需要一个载你穿梭于城市之间的人
You need someone to get you from point A to point B?
需要一个确保途中不会出现问题的人...
You need someone to make sure there's no problems along the way...
相信我 你到南方腹地
And believe me you in the deep South
肯定会有不少问题
there's gonna be problems.
所以如果你想雇我 一周付我125美元
So if you want me, it's a buck and a quarter a week.
要不你就雇刚走出去那个中国佬
Or go hire the little Chink that just pranced out of here,
看你能走多远
see how far you get.
瓦莱隆加先生
Well, Mr. Vallelonga.
谢谢你过来一趟
Thank you for stopping by.
鲍比 你好啊
Hey Bobby.
给我一杯瑞金淡啤
Give me a Rheingold.
要冰的
Ice cold.
托尼先生
Mr Tony.
奥吉问起你
Augie asking about you.
- 快点 我快渴死了 - 闭嘴 我在聊天
- Come on, I'm dying of thirst over here! - Shut up. I'm talking.
- 什么时候 - 现在
- When? - Now.
他在他的包厢里
He in his box.
托尼·利普
Tony Lip.
在科帕酒吧到底发生了什么
What the hell happened at the Copa?
我听说你把一个人的脸揍开花
I heard you split a guy's face open.
你打的那个人 迈克·沙隆
That guy you hit. Mikey Charon.
他是"魔手"查理的手下
He was one of Charie the Hand's crew.
他就该识相一点
Guess he shoulda known better.
"魔手"叫我调查此事
Hand asked me to look into it.
我找波德尔谈过了 整件事...
I spoke to Podell. Whole thing was a...
都是因一个娘们而起 对吧
over a piece of ass, right?
没错
Yeah.
俱乐部里绝对不该发生那种冲突
Beef like that should never happen inside the club.
是他们过分了
They were out of line.
所以我们把事情摆平了
So we squashed it.
你想挣点外快吗
You looking to earn a little extra scharole?
科帕关闭期间 我能给你活儿干
I can keep you busy while the Copa's down.
我要做什么
What I gotta do?
各种工作
Things...
谢谢好意 但我打算好好陪家人
Appreciate it, but I'm gonna spend some time with the family.
别傻了 你多赚点钱
Don't be stupid. You make yourself a few extra bucks,
给你那漂亮老婆买点好东西
buy something nice for that pretty little wife of yours.
不用了 我钱够用
Nah, I'm good. I'm flushed right now.
当铺
给你五十块 新年之前给我六十就把表还你
Here's fifty. Pay me sixty by New Year, you get it back.
利普 没出什么事吧
Hey Lip. Everything OK?
你闲得蛋疼吗 查理
What? You got beak trouble, Charlie?
别多管闲事
Mind your business.
快告诉我
So come on.
你去医生那儿面试得怎么样了
Dying to hear what happened with the doctor interview?
他不是真正的医生 他是弹钢琴的
He ain't a real doctor, he's a piano player.
我不懂 为什么他们说他是医生
But I don't understand, why'd they say that he was a doctor?
我也不知道
I don't know.
他好像是钢琴演奏的医生之类的
I think he's like a doctor of piano- playing or something.
有这种医生吗
You can be that?
估计有吧 他住在卡内基音乐厅楼上
I guess. He lives on top of Carnegie Hall.
你真该看看他家 小德
You shoulda seen this place, Dee.
放满雕像和各式各样的高级东西
It was filled with statues and all kinds of fancy crap.
他还穿着华丽的衣服 坐在一个王座上
And he was sitting on top of a friggin' throne all dressed up
好像他是黑鬼的国王一样
like the king of the jungle bunnies.
他是黑人吗
He's colored?
那你跟他和平相处一周都做不到
Then you wouldn't last a week with him.
钱给够了 我就可以
For right money, I would.
喂
Yeah.
是这样的...
Look. Uh...
真的吗
Really?
好的 稍等
OK. OK. Hold on a sec.
是谢利医生
It's Dr Shirley.
弹钢琴那个 他想跟你通话
The Piano guy, he wants to talk to you.
- 我吗 - 是的
- Me? - Yeah.
什么 不要
What? No!
过来 快接
Come here. Take it.
跟他聊聊
Just talk.
你好
Hello.
早安 医生 和你谈话很高兴
Good morning, Doctor, it's nice to talk to you.
没错 那确实挺久的
Yes, that is a long time...
是的
It is.
对 我很确定
Yes. I'm sure.
感谢你的来电 再见
Thank you for calling... Bye now.
他说了什么
What did he say?
他问我介不介意
He wanted to know if I'd be okay with him
他带我丈夫离家两个月
taking my husband away from his family for two months.
他说会付你你要求的酬劳
He said he'd pay you what you asked for.
那是一大笔钱
It's good money.
我们很需要
We need it.
我可没法每天吃下二十六个热狗
I can't be eatin' twenty six hot dogs every day.
我知道
I know.
我跟他说了 你可以去
I told him it was okay for you to go.
好了 酬劳先给你一半
Alright. Hey look. Here's the first half of your pay.
巡演结束后再给你剩下那一半
You're gonna get the rest when the tour's over.
- 我得按周领工资 - 抱歉
- I gotta get paid every week. - Sorry,
这不是唱片公司的规矩
that's not how the record company does it.
我们得确保你会完成工作
We gotta have some guarantee you're gonna finish the job.
我为什么不会 我都接了 不是吗
Why wouldn't I finish the job? I took it, didn't I?
那你就没什么可担心的了
Well, then you've got nothing to worry about.
是这样的 瓦莱隆加先生
Here's the deal, Mr. Vallelonga.
你的工作是准时将唐送到所有巡演地点
OK! It's your job to get Don to all his tour dates on time.
如果他错过演出
Now if he misses any shows,
你就拿不到剩下的酬劳
you're not getting your back- end.
他一场演出都不会错过的
He's not gonna miss any show.
很好 你还需要这个
Good. Oh, you're gonna need this.
这本就是我刚提到的书
Now this is the book I was telling you about.
有时你们住在同一家酒店
Sometimes you guys are staying in the same hotel,
有时不是
sometimes you're not.
舒心出行
《黑人司机的绿皮书》
- 对 - 别让我失望 走吧
- Oh yeah, I do... - Yeah, don't let me down. Let's go.
- 这就是那辆新车吗 - 对 唱片公司租的
- Is this the new one? - Yeah. The record company rented it.
- 不错吧 - 很漂亮
- Nice huh. - Beautiful.
你要离家三周
So what my sister have to say
我妹妹有什么意见吗
about you being gone for three weeks?
是八周
Eight weeks.
我敢打赌 用不了一个月
Ten- to- one, you slap this moolie out,
你就会把那黑鬼打晕 开车回来
you come home in under a month.
- 孩子们 - 跟爸爸道别
- Hi boys. - Say goodbye to your father.
弗朗基 尼基 过来
Frankie, Nicky, come here.
- 你们会乖乖的吧 - 会
- Hi, will you be good boys? - Uh huh.
- 听妈妈话 - 好
- Listen to your mother? - Uh huh.
好 亲我一下 我指望你了
Alright, give me a kiss. I'm counting on you on this.
- 别跑太远 - 好
- Don't go too far. - We won't.
- 你去汽车协会拿地图了吗 - 拿了 不
- Did you go to the A- A- A for the maps? - Yes, no.
其实是唱片公司给我的地图
I mean the record company gave me maps
还有行程表和这玩意
and the itinerary and this thing.
《黑人司机的绿皮书》
The Negro Motorist Green- Book?
上面列出黑人在南部可住宿的所有地方
Yeah, it lists all places coloreds can stay down south.
算是黑人旅行指南
Like, you know, traveling while black.
黑人旅行指南
Traveling while black?
对 如果你是黑人 出于某种原因要旅行
Yeah. If you're black and you gotta travel for some reason.
这还有专门的书吗
They had a special book for that?
我想是吧
I guess.
你带上熨斗了吗
Did you pack the iron?
我才不带熨斗 小德
I ain't lugging no iron, Dee.
那你要怎么熨裤子
How're you gonna press your pants?
我放在床垫下压平就行了
I'll put 'em under the mattress.
你一有机会
I want you to write me a letter
- 就要给我写信 - 我写不了信
- every chance you get. - I can't write letters.
- 你当然可以 - 我做不到
- Yes, you can. - I can't write.
- 花五分钟就够了 答应我 - 这太丢人了
- Take you five minutes. Promise me. - It's embarrassing.
写信没用的
They ain't gonna be no good.
写信比打长途电话便宜多了 托尼
It's a lot cheaper than calling long distance, Tony.
答应我你会写信给我
Promise me you're gonna write.
我答应你
I promise.
给 今天就存进银行
Here... Put this in the bank today.
是我一半酬劳
It's half my pay.
这几个三明治是给你和谢利医生的
Oh, here is a couple of sandwiches for you and Dr. Shirley.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 小心点 - 我会的
- Be careful. - I will.
- 我爱你 - 我也爱你 宝贝
- I love you. - I love you too, baby.
你圣诞必须回家 不然就永远别回来了
You better be home for Christmas or don't come home at all!
晚到的人没床位
知道了 老爸
I got it pop. I got it.
卡耐基音乐厅
你好 我是托尼
Hey! I'm Tony.
那个司机 给我根烟行吗
The driver. Bum a smoke?
谢谢
Thanks.
你们是乐队成员吗
So, you're with the band?
我是奥列格 大提琴手
Oleg. Cello.
我是贝斯手乔治
George. Bass.
我们不叫乐队 叫三重奏
And we're not a band, we're a trio.
三重奏
Oh, a trio?
好吧
Right.
- 早上好 - 早上好
- Good morning. - Good morning.
谢谢 阿米特
Thank you, Amit.
祝您旅途愉快 先生
Have a wonderful trip, Sir.
托尼 我们到目的地后
Tony, the first thing I'd like you to do,
你第一件事
when we arrive in the city,
就是去检查我要弹的那台钢琴
is check the piano where I'm playing,
按照合同规定 必须是斯坦威牌的
make sure it's a Steinway as per my contract.
然后你要确保
And can you see to it that
我房里有一瓶卡迪萨克威士忌
there is a bottle of Cutty Sark in my room
每晚都要有
every night.
每天晚上吗
Every night?
你要是需要有人帮你戒酒的话
Well if you ever need any help with that...
不需要
I won't.
请双手握方向盘 十点和两点方向
Ten- and- two on the wheel, please.
对了 医生
Hey Doc.
我在行程上看到
I noticed on the itinerary thing,
最后一场演出在12月23日
last show's on the 23rd December.
- 对吗 - 对 在伯明翰 圣诞演出
- Right? - Birmingham, yes. It's a Christmas show.
我们能不能第二天早点出发
So, any way we could maybe hit the road early next morning
这样来得及赶回家过平安夜
so we could be home in time for Christmas Eve?
到时候看吧
We'll see.
谢谢
Appreciate it.
你能不能把烟熄灭
Could you put out the cigarette please?
为什么
Why?
我在后面喘不上气了
I can't breath back here.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
烟都进了我的肺 大部分活都是我干的
Smoke's going into my lungs. I'm doing all the work here.
谢谢你
Thank you.
一切还好吗
没事 挺好的
好的 那我们匹兹堡旅馆见
记得预约晚餐
吃完立刻排练
你在看什么
What are you looking at?
- 你会说德语吗 - 刚才是俄语
- You speak German, huh? - That was Russian.
我之前当兵的时候被分配到德国
Yeah, I was stationed in Germany in the army.
我能听懂你们说的一部分话
I can pick up a little bit of what you're saying there.
你要小心德国佬
Watch out for them Krauts.
他们都是蛇蝎心肠
They're all snakes.
肯尼迪当初就应该把他们全炸死
Kennedy shoulda bombed 'em when he had the chance.
还有现在那群古巴暴民
Plus now them Cuban bastards.
难道他们不应该跟着我们吗
Ain't they supposed to be following us?
他们也有行程 只要能准时赶到演出现场
They have the itinerary. As long as they get to the show
我就不担心 你也不必担心
on time, I am not worried about it and neither should you.
我完全不担心
I ain't worried about nothing.
我告诉你 我担心的时候 你能看出来
Fact, when you see me worried, you'll know.
- 你绝对能看出来 - 托尼 能不能安静一会儿
- You'll know if I'm worried. - Tony. How about some quiet time?
当然
Sure.
你居然说了这句话
It's amazing you said that.
能不能安静一会儿
How about some quiet time?
德洛丽丝 我老婆 她以前总这么说
Dolores, my wife, she used to say that all time,
也不是总这么说吧 但是有时候
well not all the time, but you know...
我下班回来的时候她就会这样说
She says it when I come off from work some time,
因为她陪了孩子们一整天
you know, she's been with the kids all that day.
她就会说 托尼 能不能安静一会儿
And she would say, Tony... How about some quite time?
跟你刚才的语气一样
Exactly like how you said it.
真的 太神奇了
I mean... it's amazing.
怎么样
How was that?
很咸
Salty.
你有没有考虑过当美食评论家
Have you ever considered becoming a food critic?
没 没有啊
No... Not really.
怎么了 很赚钱吗
Why? Is there money in it?
我只是觉得
I'm just saying, you have a
你描述食物的词汇很不可思议
marvelous way with words when describing food.
很咸
Salty!
太生动了 让人几乎能尝到
So vivid. One can almost taste it.
我只是说很咸
I'm saying it's salty.
盐属于作弊行为
And salt's cheating.
任何厨师都能把食物做咸 但是不加盐
Any cook can make things salty. But to make it taste
还能做得很好吃 做出其他香味
good without the salt, with just the other flavors
这才叫本事
that's the trick.
我们得尽快出发了
We should really get going soon
还想在晚饭前赶到匹兹堡
if we expect to get to Pittsburgh by dinner.
我以前当兵的时候
When I was in the army
认识一个匹兹堡来的人
I knew a guy from Pittsburgh
但是他称之为奶子堡
except he called it Tits- burgh
他说那里的女人奶子都很大
he said all the women there have huge tits.
太荒谬了
That's absurd.
为什么匹兹堡的女人
Why would women in Pittsburgh
会比纽约的女人胸部大呢
have larger breasts than, say, women in New York?
很快我们就能一探究竟了
Guess we'll find out, huh?
其实 你最开始雇用我的时候
You know, when you first hired me
我老婆买了一张你的唱片
my wife went out bought one of your records,
关于孤儿的那个
one about the orphans.
孤儿
Orphans?
对 封面上有一群小孩坐在篝火边
Yeah. Cover had a bunch of kids sitting around a campfire?
那是奥菲斯[发音类似]
Orpheus.
对
Yeah.
《地狱中的奥菲斯》 根据法国歌剧创作的
Orpheus in the Underworld. It's based on a French Opera.
而且封面上也不是小孩
And those weren't children on the cover.
都是地狱里的恶魔
Those were demon in the bowels of hell.
真的假的 那这些孩子以前肯定很淘气
No shit. Must have been naughty kids.
- 你要干什么 - 我得尿一泡 医生
- What are you doing? - I gotta take a leak. Doc.
- 在这里 现在吗 - 你要我尿裤子里吗
- Here? Now? - You want me to piss my pants?
宾夕法尼亚州 匹兹堡市
医生 下午好
Oh hey Doc, good afternoon.
这笔钱给你做我们的杂费开销用
Take this for any incidentals we may need.
如果你想买什么东西
If you want to buy something,
不必问我 留好收据就行
you don't have to ask, just keep the receipt please.
如果钱不够了就告诉我
When it runs low let me know.
谢谢
Oh, thanks.
还有一件事
One more thing.
音乐会前后 我们会参加许多活动
We will be attending many events before and after the concerts
会接触到全国上下
interacting with some of
一些很富有也很有修养的人们
the wealthiest and most highly- educated people in the country.
我觉得你有时候的措辞
It is my feeling that your diction
也许在三州地区很有魅力 但是在这里...
however charming it may be in the tri- state area, could use some
有待提高
finessing.
你说的措辞 是什么意思
You mean diction, like in what way?
措辞这个词 还能有什么意思
Like in the only way the word is ever used.
好
Okay.
你的语气 音调 还有词语的选择
Your intonation, inflection, your choice of words.
我自己的麻烦就够多了 现在还要操心
I got my own problems, now I gotta worry about
别人对我说话方式有什么看法吗
what people think about the way I talk?
我可以教你一些简单的技巧
There are simple techniques I can
这些技巧很有用 我可以帮你
teach you that are quite effective. I can help you.
我他妈不需要你帮忙
I don't need no goddamn help.
有人不喜欢我说话的方式 那就自己玩蛋去
People don't like the way I talk, they can go take a shit.
你的粗口也是一个问题
The profanity is another issue.
妈了个巴子 你找我茬干什么
A fanabla, why you breaking my balls?
因为你可以做到更好 瓦莱隆加先生
Because you can do better. Mr Vallelonga.
这让我想到另一件事
Which brings me to one more point
作为特邀贵宾
as the guest of honor,
我参加这些活动时会被介绍
I will be introduced when entering these intimate events.
他们也会介绍你
You will be introduced as well.
我个人认为
In my humble opinion
瓦莱隆加可能有点难发音
Vallelonga may be difficult to pronounce.
所以我觉得...
So, I was thinking...
瓦莱可能更好些 托尼·瓦莱
Valle would be more appropriate. Tony Valle.
简单又干练
Short and sweet.
不行
Nah!
要是对瓦莱隆加有意见 可以叫我托尼· 利普
If they got a problem with Vallelonga, they can call me Tony Lip.
这些都是上流人士 托尼·利普可能有点...
These are genteel people. Tony Lip might be a little...
太世俗了
worldly for them.
那就叫我托尼·瓦莱隆加
Well, then it's Tony Vallelonga.
这些高档人士
All these high- class people,
比我聪明那么多 他们那么有智慧
so much smarter than me, with their intelligence
那么会说话
and speaking abilities,
难道还叫不出我的名字吗
you're telling me they can't pronounce my name?
他们要是不喜欢
They don't like it, they can
那就给老子憋着 我在外面等就好
shove it up their ass, I'll just wait outside.
这算是个办法
That sound compromised.
女士们先生们 今天晚上
Ladies and gentlemen, tonight we are
我们有幸请到了一位优秀的美国艺术家
privileged to present a great American artist.
他在三岁时就第一次登台演出
He gave his first public performance at the age of three.
在十八岁的时候 他受阿瑟·菲德勒邀请
At age eighteen, at Arthur Fiedler's invitation,
与波士顿流行乐团进行了人生首场音乐会
our guest made his concert debut with the Boston Pops.
他拥有心理学 音乐学
He holds Doctorates in Psychology,
以及礼仪艺术学的博士学位
in Music, and in the Liturgical Arts
在过去一年多的时间里
and he had performed at
他已经在白宫演出过两次
the White House twice in the past fourteen months.
他是真正的大师
He is a true virtuoso.
大师 这是意大利语
Virtuoso... that's Italian.
就是说他很厉害
Means he's really good.
女士们先生们 有请唐·谢利三重奏
So Ladies and gentleman, please welcome The Don Shirley Trio!
- 两个五 真走运 - 他一直在赢
- Hard ten! Lady's friend. - He keeps on winning!
这是你们的骰子 我只是今晚手气好
Hey, it's your dice, I'm just having a lucky night.
老兄 你在作弊
You cheating, brother!
托尼
Tony.
老大在找你了
Boss man's calling.
他不是我老大 我是给唱片公司干活的
He ain't my boss. I work for the record company.
我也是给唱片公司干活
I work for the record company too.
别这样 给我们个机会把钱赢回来
Come on man! Give us a chance to win back our loot!
抱歉了各位 使命在身
I'm sorry, fellas, duty calls!
使命在身
Duty calls?
兄弟 我的使命就是把钱赢回来
Look man, my duty is getting my money back.
我一直在找你
I've been looking for you.
抱歉 我之前在跟他们玩游戏
Yeah sorry. The guys were having a little game.
你下次需要钱的时候 直接问我就好
Next time you need extra money, you just ask me.
赢钱更有趣
More fun winning it.
如果你输了呢
Then what if you lost?
骰子和牌 我不会输的 医生
Craps and cards, I don't lose, Doc.
我不会输
I don't lose.
单膝跪在全是沙砾的路边
So stooping down in the gravel
丢骰子来赚几个零钱 你就是赢家了吗
pitching dice for pocket change makes you a winner?
你为什么要奚落我 大家都这样啊
What are you giving me shit for? Everybody was doing it.
他们无法选择是进去还是出来
They didn't have a choice whether to be inside or out.
而你可以
You did.
拍拍膝盖吧 全是灰
And wipe off your knees, you have dirt on them.
俄亥俄州
亲爱的德洛丽丝 你好吗 我挺好的
Dear Dolores... How are you? I am fine...
我吃得很好 主要是吃汉堡
I'm eating real good, hamburgers mostly
所以不必担心我吃得好不好
so don't worry about me not eating good.
我今天晚上看到谢利医生弹钢琴了
I saw Dr. Shirley play the piano. Tonight.
他弹琴的感觉不像黑人
He doesn't play like a colored guy.
他弹得像利伯雷斯 甚至更好[美国钢琴家]
He plays like Liberace but better.
他应该是个天才吧
He's like a genius I think.
我从后视镜里看他的时候
When I look at him in the rear- view mirror,
能看出来他一直在想事情
I can tell he's always thinking about stuff in his head.
天才大概都是这样吧
I guess that's what geniuses do.
但是这么聪明似乎也并不开心
But it don't look fun to be that smart.
我非常非常想你
I miss you very very much.
- 这是谁 - 谁
- Who is this? - Who?
广播里的
On the radio?
小理查德
Lil' Richard.
真的吗 这是小理查德
Really? That's Little Richard?
对 你能弹出这种音乐吗 医生
Yeah. Think you could play something like this, Doc?
不知道 听起来很复杂
I don't know. Sounds very complicated.
可不是吗
Ain't that right.
你这个托尼·利普·嘴哥的称呼哪里来的
So where did this Tony the Lip moniker come from?
不是托尼·利普·嘴哥
It's not Tony the Lip.
就是托尼·利普 两个词
It's Tony Lip. One word.
我小时候的绰号 因为我的朋友们说
I got it when I was a kid. Because my friends
我是布朗克斯区最能扯犊子的
said I was the best bullshit artist in the Bronx.
- 你为什么在笑 - 什么意思
- Why are you smiling? - What do you mean?
你的朋友 你最亲近的人
It doesn't bother you that your friends,
认为你是骗子 你难道不介意吗
the people closest to you, consider you a liar?
谁说骗子了 我说的是扯犊子
Who said liar? I said bullshit artist.
- 有什么区别 - 我从来不说谎
- Then what's the difference? - Cause I don't lie. Ever.
我只是擅长说服人们
I'm just good at talking people into,
去做他们不想做的事
you know, doing things they don't wanna do.
跟他们胡扯
By bullshittin' em.
你感觉很骄傲吗
And you're proud of that?
它让我得到了这份工作
Well it got me this job.
等等 你在胡说吧
Wait a minute. You're full of shit!
你从没听说过恰比·却克吗
You never heard of Chubby Checker?
我当然听说过他 只是之前没有听过他的音乐
Of course I've heard of him, I just never heard his music before.
但我很喜欢 这音乐很棒
But I like this. This is nice.
- 他的声音很柔和 很细腻 - 棒极了
- He's got a silky voice... very smooth. - Yeah, it's terrific.
现在大家跳舞都听他的音乐
This is what everybody is dancing to now.
看路 托尼
Eyes on the road Tony.
你知道这首歌吗
You know this song?
- 不 我不知道 - 你怎么会不知道这首歌
- I don't think so. No. - How could you not know this music?
艾瑞莎·弗兰克林
Aretha Frankin.
恰比·却克 小理查德 山姆·库克
Chubby Checker, Lil' Richard, Sam Cooke.
拜托 医生 这些是著名的黑人歌手
I mean come on Doc, these are your people!
- 你想要什么吗 我去买包烟 - 不 谢谢
- You want anything? I'm gonna pack smokes. - No thank you.
屋内称重
谢谢你 奥列格
Thank you, Oleg.
真棒 迈克 他编了什么瞎话
Nice turn Mike, what he makes it up?
吃个苹果吧 医生
Snatch an apple Doc.
在出发前 我们得谈谈 托尼
Before we pull out Tony, we need to have a talk.
- 谈什么 - 奥列格把你干的事告诉我了
- Yeah? - Oleg told me what you did.
我干了什么
What I do?
你从店里偷了一块玉石
You stole a jade stone from the store.
- 不 我没有 - 他看到了你这么干
- No I didn't. - He watched you do it.
我没有偷石头
I didn't steal no stone.
你把它捡起来 放进口袋了
You picked it up and you put it in your pocket.
我从地上捡了一块石头
I picked up a rock up off the ground.
没有偷盒子里的
I didn't steal from the box.
你为什么要捡地上的石头
Now why would you pick up a rock off the ground?
我不知道
I don't know.
因为那不是偷窃 只是一块普通的石头
'Cause that ain't stealing. Just a regular rock.
你为什么想要一块普通的石头
And why would you want a regular rock?
为了拥有
To have.
- 也许为了拥有幸运 - 一块幸运石
- For luck maybe. - A lucky rock.
- 对 - 给我看看
- Yeah. - Let me see it.
拿着它回去付钱
Take it back and pay for it.
我跟你说过那个德国佬是个告密小人
I told you that Kraut was a sneak.
用我没干过的事出卖我
Rats me out for something I didn't even do.
快去付石头的钱 托尼 你会好受点
Pay for the stone, Tony, you'll feel better.
我感觉很好
I feel fine.
我不会为我在泥土里发现的普通石头付钱
And I ain't paying for no regular rock I found in the dirt.
别开车 瓦莱隆加先生
Do not drive, Mr. Vallelonga.
把它放回去
Put it back.
- 感觉好点了吗 - 没有
- Feel better? - No.
托尼 你要是乐意 我很乐意给你买下它
If you'd like, Tony, I'd happily buy you the stone.
不用了 你把乐子都搞没了
Don't bother. You took all the fun out of it.
汉诺威市
印第安纳州
打扰一下 先生
Excuse me, sir.
- 我是乐队的人 - 你们的东西都准备好了
- I'm with the band. - You're all set up.
- 这不是我们要用的钢琴吧 - 就是它
- This isn't the piano, right? - That's it.
它不是斯坦威牌的
It ain't a Steinway.
所以呢
So what?
谢利医生只弹斯坦威牌的钢琴
Dr. Shirley only plays on Steinway- brand pianos.
合同里写好的
It's in his written contract.
- 谢利医生是谁 - 谢利医生...
- Who's Dr. Shirley? - Dr. Shirley...
谢利先生三重奏
the Don Shirley Trio?
他们今晚要进行演奏
They're playing tonight.
- 这很重要吗 - 是的 对这个合同很重要
- Does it really matter? - Yeah, it does, to this contract.
算了吧兄弟 不管准备什么
Come on man, these coons
这些黑鬼都会照样弹
can play on anything you put in front of them.
但这台钢琴太烂了
But it's a piece of shit.
里面还有垃圾
And there is garbage in there.
- 那就把它搬出去 - 你说什么
- So, take it out. - What'd you say?
你没听错
You heard me.
你还有两三个小时 找台干净的斯坦威钢琴来
Hey, you got 2- 3 hours. Just get a clean Steinway in here.
- 学校里没有斯坦威钢琴 - 这不关我事
- There ain't no Steinway on campus. - Not my problem.
我敢肯定整个印第安纳州都没有两台斯坦威钢琴
I bet there is not two Steinways in the whole state of Indiana.
那你最好动作麻利点
I guess you better move your ass then.
你以为你在跟谁说话 意大利佬
Who do you think you're talking to, grease ball?
斯坦威
亲爱的德洛丽丝...今天早餐我吃了牛排和鸡蛋
Dear Dolores... This morning I had steak and eggs. For breakfast.
这个乐队一直在豪华的夜总会演出
The band has been playing at very ritzy joints.
我和谢利医生相处得很好 但有时候
Dr. Shirley and I are getting along pretty good, but sometimes
锡达拉皮兹市
爱荷华州
他会很悲伤 因此他总是买醉
I think he gets sad and that's why he drinks too much.
我以前从不知道这个国家有多美
I never knew how very beautiful this country was.
现在亲眼看到才知道
Now that I'm seeing it I know.
你不会相信大自然有多美
You won't believe how beautiful nature is,
就像他们说的一样美
it is as beautiful as they say.
这边的交通情况
And the traffic out here
对我来说没什么问题
in the country is nothing, which is fine by me.
现在我正在一间餐厅吃意式肉丸面
Right now I'm eating spaghetti and meatballs
这吃起来就像中式面条上的番茄酱一样
in a diner that tastes like ketchup on Chinese noodles.
我们现在要南下... 到了南方后
We are heading down south now... I will write you
我会再给你写一封信 我爱你
another letter when we get down south. I love you.
你的丈夫托尼 替我亲亲孩子们
Your husband Tony. P.S. Kiss the kids for me.
欢迎来到肯塔基州
你有家人吗 医生
You got any family, Doc?
- 算不上有 - 算不上有吗
- Not really. - Not really?
要么有 要么没有
Either you do or you don't.
说来话长 托尼
It's a long story, Tony.
怎么 我们现在很赶时间吗
What, we're in a hurry now?
说说看吧
Let's hear it.
我有个弟弟
I have a brother somewhere.
我们以前经常聚在一起...
We used to get together once in a while...
但后来越来越难保持联系
but it got more and more difficult to stay in touch.
这大概是做音乐家的诅咒吧
Curse of being a musician I guess.
总是四处奔波
Always on the road
就像狂欢节工作者一样
like a carnival worker.
或是罪犯
Or a criminal.
我的婚姻也受到了很大的影响
Took quite a toll on my marriage as well.
- 你结婚了吗 - 结过
- You're married? - Was.
她叫琼 是个好人
June, good person.
语法很糟糕 但很善良
Terrible grammar, but a kind soul.
- 你会很喜欢她的 - 琼吗
- You'll quite like her. - June?
就像莱西的妈妈一样吗
Like uh, like Lessie's mom?
不幸的是 我没能做好
Unfortunately, I couldn't
一个丈夫和一个音乐会钢琴演奏家
do a husband act and a concert pianist act.
我似乎不能兼顾这两个角色
Couldn't seem to manage both worlds.
前方一千六百米处
肯德基
Kentucky Fried Chicken.
就在肯塔基州 你说巧不巧
In Kentucky! When's that ever gonna happen?!
肯德基
一美元 如此美味
即刻享受或打包回家
好吧
All right!
你要吃什么吗
Hey, you want some?
不用了 谢谢你 托尼
I'm fine. Thank you Tony.
我觉得这是我吃过最好吃的肯德基
I think this is the best Kentucky Fried Chicken I ever had.
我猜这里的更新鲜 对吧
But I guess it's fresher down here, right?
我从没见过像你这么有胃口的人
I don't think I've ever met anyone with your appetite.
不 我买了一桶 你可以尝尝
No, I've bought the bucket so you could have some.
我这辈子从没吃过炸鸡
I've never had fried chicken in my life.
你在胡说什么 你们黑人很喜欢
Who you bullshittin'? You people love
炸鸡 粗燕麦粉 五颜六色的蔬菜
the fried chicken, the grits, the colored greens
我也很喜欢
I love it, too.
我在军队的时候 黑人厨师总是做这些吃的
The negro cooks used to make it all time when I was in the army.
你对我的评价很狭隘 托尼
You have a very narrow assessment of me, Tony.
对吧 我很厉害
Yeah right? I'm good.
不 你不是厉害 是糟糕
No, you're not good, you're bad.
我的意思是 别的黑人
I'm saying, just because
喜欢听某种类型的音乐
other Negros enjoy certain types of music,
不代表我就必须喜欢
it doesn't mean I have to.
也不代表我们都吃同一种食物
Nor do we all have to eat the same kind food.
等等 你要是说所有
Wait a minute. If you said all
意大利人都喜欢吃披萨和意式肉丸面
guineas like pizza and spaghetti and meatballs
- 我不会感到被侮辱 - 你没理解我的意思
- I'm not gonna get insulted. - Well, you're missing the point.
你认定每一个黑人...
For you to make the assumption that every Negro...
- 你要吃吗 - 不
- Hey, you want some or not? - No.
给 吃点吧
Here. Come on.
- 它的味道不好闻吗 - 闻起来还行
- Tell me that don't smell good? - It smells okay
我不想把油弄到毯子上
I prefer not to get grease on my blanket.
我会把油弄到毯子上 拜托 尝尝吧
Ooh, I'm gonna get grease on my blankie. Come on, have a piece.
要不了你的命 来 放轻松
It ain't gonna kill ya. Come on. Take it easy.
- 不要 - 快拿着
- No. - Take it.
- 我要丢到后面去 - 你敢
- I'm gonna throw it in the back. - Don't you dare.
- 那你最好拿着 - 这怎么吃
- Then you better take it. - How?
你有盘子吗 或是餐具
Do you have plates? Or utensils?
见鬼了 用手吃啊
Bah fongool! Eat it with your hands,
- 你就应该这么吃 - 我做不到
- that's how you're supposed to. - I can't do that.
吃了它吧 快拿着 拿着
Eat it. Come on. Take it. Take it. Take it.
我得开车 握好方向盘
I gotta drive. Ten and two on the wheels.
快拿着 拿着
Come on. Take it. Take it. Come on. Come on.
这就对了
There you go.
- 我做不到 托尼 - 赶紧吃了
- I- I can't do this Tony. - Eat the goddamn thing.
天哪
Jesus.
怎么样 不好吃吗
What, no good?
就是...
Just seems...
太不卫生了
so unsanitary.
谁会在乎
Who gives a shit?
放轻松 好好享受吧
Just relax and enjoy it.
我父亲过去常说
You know my father used to say,
不管你做什么 都要全力以赴
whatever you do, do it a hundred percent.
工作时 努力工作 大笑时 尽情地笑
When you work, work, when you laugh, laugh,
吃东西时 要像在吃最后一餐一样去享受
when you eat, eat like it's your last meal.
你还要吃吗 给 吃块鸡胸肉
You want another piece? Here, have a breast.
很好吃
Delicious.
拿着 这就对了
Take it. There you go.
这些骨头怎么处理
What do we do about the bones?
这样
We do this.
我们就这样处理
This is what we do.
这就对了
There you go.
这有什么大不了 松鼠会吃掉它的
What's the big deal with that? Squirrels will eat it anyway.
- 把它捡起来 托尼 - 大自然会处理好的
- Pick it up, Tony. - Nature takes care of the earth.
- 快捡起来 - 老天爷 ty
- Pick it up. - Jeez.
路易斯维尔
肯塔基州
仅限黑人入住
不可能是这里
This can't be right.
《绿皮书》上说
Says right here.
如家一般的温暖舒适
Cozy as your own home.
这地方看着像一坨屎
Place looks like my ass.
就是这里没错
This is the place.
方形的那个就行
Square one please.
- 就这一个吗 - 谢谢
- Just this one? - Thank you.
你...
Hey... Uh...
你要是有任何需要
If you need anything,
我就在街边的伊斯顿旅馆
I'll be right up the street at the Easton Inn.
谢谢你 托尼
Thank you Tony.
弗洛伊德 我们准备好了
Hey Floyd, we ready?
图利 我玩不了 肩膀不行
Tulley, I can't play, my shoulder.
你和你那破肩膀
You and that damn shoulder.
靓仔 你要一起玩吗
Hey, hey fancy- pants, you wanna play?
- 你说什么 - 来吧兄弟 我们三缺一
- I beg your pardon. - Come on brother, we short a man.
我...我还是不玩了
I... I'd rather not.
怎么 你太高太壮了吗
What, you too high and mighty?
不 不 算了吧 算了吧
No, no. Let him alone, let him alone.
他就是怕弄脏他的管家制服
He's just afraid of getting that butler uniform all that dusty!
我就是...
I'm just...
我要去见一个朋友
I'm on my way to meet a friend.
谢谢你没帮上忙
Yeah, well thanks for nothing?
- 弗洛伊德 快来 - 闭嘴 别打扰我
- Floyd, come on man. - Shut your ass up man, leave me alone.
伊斯顿旅馆
《黑人司机的绿皮书》
和平度假
Vacation without aggravation.
奎恩宾馆
杰拉尔德餐厅
为特定的人准备美味的晚餐
Delightful dinners for particular people.
- 谁啊 - 起来 我是乔治 快起来
- Yeah? - Get up! It's George. Get up.
托尼快点 快开门
Tony come on. Hurry up!
谢利医生有麻烦了
Dr. Shirley's in trouble.
我去喝酒 走进一家酒吧
I went out for a drink, I walk into this bar,
看到谢利医生正被一伙人揍
and Dr Shirley's in there getting bounced around!
我不想抛下他 但我不知道怎么办
I didn't want to leave him, but I didn't know what to do!
谁把他放出笼子的
Who let him out of his cage?
还给他戴了领带
And they put that little tie on him too?
你这是扮成谁
Who you are dressed out?
放开他
Get your hands off him.
看看这是谁来了 伙计们
What in the good goddamn we got here, fellas?
把他交过来 我们走人 什么事都没有
Hand him over, we walk out, won't be a problem.
我只是想喝杯酒 托尼
I just wanted a drink, Tony.
我告诉你了 我们这就走 没什么
Hey, I told you, we'll leave. Not a big deal.
快点 他哪也不去
Come on. He ain't going nowhere,
我们正需要一个钢丝球来刷碗
we need a Brillo pad to wash these dishes with.
听着 混蛋们 帮自己个忙 放他走
Listen assholes, do yourself a favor and let him go.
快点
Now!
客气点说
Say it nice.
我刚客气说过了
I just said it nice.
这家伙要得到他应得的惩罚
This boy's gonna get what he's got coming to him.
而你...轮不到你说话
And you... you ain't got no say!
也许吧
Maybe.
但不管发生什么 我都要朝你的
But, whatever happens here, I'm gonna put a bullet
大脑门中间射发子弹
right in the middle of your thick skull.
他没有枪 雷
He ain't got no gun, Ray.
他满嘴胡话
He's fulla shit.
万一他是认真的呢
What if he ain't?
反正我是认真的
Well, I sure ain't.
我可不会让你们在我的地盘闹这一出
And I ain't about to let this come to pass in my place.
放这黑人走 让他走
Let the spook go. Let him go.
快点
Come on.
把他带走
Get him outta here.
我想让这些北方佬滚出我的地盘
I want these Yankees off from my property.
- 回家吧 - 快点乔治 快走
- Go home. - Come on George, go, go.
我扶着你呢
I got you, Doc.
回家
Go home.
你疯了吗
You out of your mind?
抱歉 我不是故意让你为难的
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to put you in that position.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait!
你又要吐了
You wanna throw up again?
我没事
I'm OK.
老实说 医生 我搞不懂你
Honest to God Doc, I don't understand you.
你可以在这喝酒的 你有一整瓶酒
You could have drunk here. You got a whole bottle.
- 我只需要点新鲜空气 - 空气
- I just needed some air. - Air?
你知道自己在哪吗
Do you know where you are?
地理条件真的重要吗
Does the geography really matter?
- 什么 - 如果我在酒吧
- What? - If I was in a bar...
在你住处附近 我们的...
in your neighborhood, would...
对话会有所不同吗
the conversation be any different?
从现在开始 少了我你哪也不许去
From now on you don't go nowhere without me.
哪也别去
Nowhere!
- 明白了吗 - 我明白
- Got it? - I understand.
- 你的房间在哪 - 托尼
- Where is your room? - Tony.
怎么了
What?
你真有枪吗
Do you really have a gun?
当然没有
'Course not.
医生 房间在哪
Doc, where's your goddamn room?
- 在那 - 起来 在那边
- There it is. - Come on. Over there?
我送你上床 医生
Let me get you to bed, Doc.
你明晚有个重要的演出 来吧
You got a big show tomorrow night. C'mon.
路易斯维尔 谢谢你们的热情款待
Louisville. Thank you for your warm hospitality!
谢谢大家
Thank you.
- 别偷懒 练习发音 - 我没有
- Don't be lazy Tony, enunciate. - I ain't.
- 红凤凰 粉凤凰 红粉凤凰花凤凰 - 红凤凰
- Betty bought a bit of better butter. - Betty bought.
红凤凰 粉... 花凤凰...
Betty bought... butter...
谁这么说话
Who says that?
花凤凰...
Butter uh...
你必须迈出这一步 托尼
you have to start somewhere Tony.
歌手会进行发声练习
A singer does vocal exercises,
排练之前 运动员会热身
an athlete warms up, before they rehearse.
运动员锻炼 他们不排练
Athletes practice, they don't rehearse.
该死
Ah, shit!
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
罗利
北卡罗来纳州
有请来自遥远北方的特别来宾
our very special guest from the far north...
唐·谢利
Don Shirley!
陪同谢利先生的是三重奏的成员
Accompanying Mr. Shirley, the members of his trio...
奥列格·马拉科夫 乔治·戴尔 以及助理
Oleg Malakhov, George Dyer, and his associate,
托尼·瓦莱... 瓦莱朗吉亚
Tony Vallla... Valleg... Valle... Valley... lohnja.
这是我亲爱的妻子玛格丽特
This is my lovely wife Margaret.
如果你们不介意
If you gentlemen don't mind,
我要带小唐去介绍一圈
I'm going to steal Donnie away for some introductions.
- 那是什么 - 辣椒奶酪三明治 先生
- What's that? - Pimiento- cheese sandwich, sir.
我尝尝
Yeah, I'll try that one.
抱歉 不是我的菜
Sorry! Not for me.
这周早些时候我们求助
Earlier this week, we asked our help
谢利先生晚餐会想吃什么
what Mr. Shirley might like for supper.
所以厨师们
So the boys in the kitchen
准备了特别的餐点招待贵宾
whipped up a special menu in honor of our guest.
先生们
Gentlemen.
自制炸鸡
Home cooked fried chicken.
来吧 端上来 趁热端上来
There you go. Bring them in. Serve it up hot.
谢谢
Thank you.
休息片刻我们再回来
We return after a brief intermission.
- 打扰下 唐 演出很成功 - 谢谢
- Excuse me, Don. Lovely work in there. - Well, thank you!
你在找便桶吗 我来帮你
Are you looking for the commode? Here, let me help you.
就在那棵松树前面
Right out there 'fore that pine.
我不想用那间
I'd prefer not to use that.
别犯傻 唐 里面没看上去那么糟
Well, don't be silly, Don. It looks a lot worse from the outside.
看来你亲身体验过了
And I'd suppose you'd know from experience.
从没有人抱怨过
What? Never had any complains.
我可以回旅馆 用那里的厕所
Well, I could return to my motel and use the facilities there.
但至少要花半个小时
But... that would take at least a half an hour.
我们不介意等
We don't mind waiting.
干嘛不停在路边 你去树林里解决
Why don't I just pull over... You can piss in the woods?
动物才在树林里小便
Animals go in the woods.
但如果回你的旅馆
But it's gonna be at least twenty minutes if
至少要花上二十分钟
I gotta go all the way back to your motel.
所以我们快去吧 这样早点回去完成演出
So let's just get there so I can go back and finish the show.
看吧 这就是你和我的不同
See, that's the difference between you and me.
- 我对去树林里小便完全没问题 - 我知道
- I'd have zero problem goin' in the woods. - I'm well aware.
你冲我发火干嘛 又不是我定的规矩
Why you sore at me? I don't make the rules down here.
不是 那是谁
No? Then who does?
你的意思是就因为我是白人
You saying just 'cause I'm white
他们也是白人
and they're white?
你刚才说的话是彻头彻尾的偏见
You know, that's a very prejudice thing you just said there.
彻头彻尾
A very prejudice thing.
我跟第二大道上熟食店的犹太人的共同点
I got more in common with the hymies at Second Avenue Deli
都比跟那帮混蛋乡巴佬多
than I do with these hillbilly pricks down here.
- 注意看路 - 你一不喜欢听我说的话
- Eyes on the road. - You always say that when you
- 就说这句 - 注意看路
- don't like what I'm saying. - Eyes on the road!
我不明白
I don't get it.
他怎么还能和颜悦色 跟他们握手
How does he smile and shake their hands like that?
要是他们让我去室外上厕所
If they tried to pull that outhouse shit on me,
老子就尿他们厅里的地板上
I'd piss right on their living room floor.
别那样
Don't do that.
我们还有还多演奏会要去
We have many concert dates left.
所以呢
Yeah... So...?
你知道我们有合同义务把它们履行完吧
You realize we are contractually obliged to perform them?
当然了
Of course I do.
你不演出 我们就拿不到钱
You don't play, we don't get paid.
你想说什么
What's your point?
这种难堪的场面还会出现
Ugly circumstances are going to happen again.
- 控制好自己 - 别冲我说教 你个混账
- So control yourself. - Don't lecture me, you rat.
谢利医生本可以待在北方
Dr. Shirley could've stayed up north
在公园大道的宴会演出 接受奉承
getting rear- end kissed at Park Avenue parties
拿着三倍的酬劳
for three times money
但他却选择南下
but he asked for this.
为什么
Why?
你到底在做什么
What on God's green earth are you doing?
写信
A letter.
看上去更像是结构松散的勒索信
Looks more like a piecemeal ransom note.
我能看看吗
May I?
亲爱的 德洛丽丝
Dear, Dolores...
没拼对 不是那个"鹿"
D- E- A- R, this isn't animal.
我正在和城里的高官要员见面
I'm meeting all the highly leading citizens of the town.
用高级词汇的那些人
People that use big words, all of them
但你知道我的 我混得过去
but you know me, I get by,
我很擅长扯淡
I'm a good bullshitter.
应该双写T
Two "t"s in bullshitter.
写这封信的同时 我在吃薯片
As I'm writing this letter, I'm eating potato chips
开始有些口渴了
and I'm starting to get thirsty.
我洗了袜子 晾在电视上
I washed my socks and dried them on the TV.
我应该"戴"熨斗的
I should have brung the iron.
你知道这很可悲吧
You know this is pathetic right?
告诉我你想说什么
Tell me what you're trying to say.
- 我很想她之类的 - 可不是吗
- You know, how I miss her and shit. - You didn't say that.
但用一些别出心裁的方式表达出来
But do it in a manner that no one else has ever done it before.
也别用脏话
And without the profanity.
比如... 写下来
Something like... Put this down.
- 亲爱的德洛丽丝 - 不是吧
- Dear Dolores... - Oh God no!
亲- 爱- 的 德洛丽丝
D- E- A- R, Dolores.
当我想到你
When I think of you...
我就想起爱荷华州美丽的平原
I'm reminded of the beautiful plains of Iowa.
什么飞机
What planes?
平原 我们见到的成片的土地
The plains. P- L- A- I- N- S. Those big fields we saw.
那些确实不错 平原
Yeah, those were nice. PLAINS.
这儿的人都这么称呼大片的土地
Which what they call big fields around here.
托尼 别加注释
Tony, no expounding.
- 啥玩意 - 照我说的写就行
- A what? - Just write what I say.
- 行了 - 我们之间的距离
- I'm good. - The distance between us
让我魂牵梦绕
is breaking my spirit...
我们之间...
between us...
没有你 我的时间和经历都毫无意义
My time and experiences without you are meaningless to me.
与你相爱是我做过的最轻松的事
Falling in love with you was the easiest thing I have ever done.
与你相爱...
Falling... in love... with you...
太他妈浪漫了
is very fucking romantic.
是我做过的最轻松的事
It was the easiest thing I have ever done.
对我来说 你最重要
Nothing matters to me but you.
我活着的每一天 都将它铭记于心
And everyday I am alive, I'm aware of this.
遇见你的那天我就爱上了你 今天我也爱你
I loved you the day I met you, I love you today...
余生我也都会一样爱你
And I will love you to rest of my life.
- 我用加上附言 亲亲孩子们吗 - 附言
- So can I put the P.S., kiss the kids? - A P.S.?
对 就像结尾
Yeah, like a the end.
那就像在肖斯塔科维奇第七交响曲结尾摇响牛铃一样
That's like clanging a cowbell at the end of Shostakovitch's 7th.
所以...是好的吧
Right... So that's good?
简直完美 托尼
It's perfect, Tony.
梅肯
佐治亚州
大家都在谈论1954年的威利·梅斯
Everybody talks about Willie Mays, 1954,
但他在马球球场都算不上最出色的接球手
who wasn't even the greatest catcher in the polo grounds.
最棒的是乔·迪马吉奥 在1936年
That was Joe DiMaggio, 1936, 2nd game
世职棒第二场 最后一记接杀 500英尺
at world eries, final out, 500 feet...
你喜欢吗 医生
Do you like that, Doc?
- 这套西装很帅气 - 不错
- That's a handsome suit. - Sharp.
这家伙和你很像
Guy looks just like you.
是吗
He does?
体型上很像
Size- wise. Yeah!
他看起来大约42码
He's about a forty two.
要不穿上身试试看
Why don't you try on that?
怎么 你每晚都要在舞台上穿燕尾服吗
What, you gotta wear a tuxedo on stage every night?
你可以混着穿穿
You could mix it up a little back.
穿上看看吧 我们有的是时间
Now, see how that looks on you. We got plenty of time.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
- 你好 - 先生 您需要什么吗
- How you doing? - May I help you sir?
嗯 我们想试试橱窗展示的那套帅气灰色西装
Yeah. We wanna try on that beautiful Grey suit in the window.
- 有42码的吗 - 当然
- You got it in a 42? - Of course.
- 就是这个 - 试衣间在后面 先生
- That's the one. - Dressing room's in the back, sir.
谢谢 我马上就好
Thank you. That'll be just a moment.
别着急 医生 我给你找找合适的领带
Take your time Doc, I'll check out some ties for you.
抱歉 你不能试那件衣服
Uh, excuse me, you're not allowed to try that on.
什么
I beg your pardon?
如果你先买下来
If you would like to purchase it first,
我们很高兴根据你的需求来改尺寸
we'll be happy to tailor it to your needs.
明白了
I see.
喂
Yeah?
是我
That's me.
青年会
梅肯
长官 我接到了有关谢利医生的电话
Hey officer, I got a call about Dr. Shirley.
跟我来
Come on.
他有朋友在
His friend's here.
谢谢
Thank you.
老天爷 给他一条毛巾
Give the guy a towel, for Chrissakes?
- 你是律师 - 不
- You the lawyer? - No.
你该叫律师过来 我们要把这个同性恋关起来
Well you should call one. We're taking your Auntie in.
为什么
For what?
经理抓到他和另一个人...
Manager caught him and the other guy...
能把他的手铐给取下来吗
Can't we get the cuffs off him,
让他穿上裤子 我们再谈这件事
let him put his pants on? We talk about this?
我们当然可以 但我们不会这么做
Sure we could. But we ain't.
听着 我们明早就离开了
OK, look, we're out of here tomorrow morning...
你再也见不到我们了
you'll never see us again.
总会有办法解决这个事的
There's gotta be something due to work this out.
要不你让他走
What if, uh, you let him go,
我给点东西你们表示感谢
and I give you something to thank you?
- 你在贿赂我们 - 不 才不是 就是个礼物
- You bribing us? - No. Hell no. A gift.
- 表达感谢 - 哪种感谢
- A thank you. - What kind of thank you?
就像 向警察机关捐款 捐给你们
Like... A donation to the police force. To you guys.
随你们开口
Whatever you want.
你们喜欢西装吗
You like suits?
我今天穿过你们美丽的小镇
I was walking through your nice town today,
看到一个卖西装的服装店
and I seen a store that was selling suits.
高级西装
Primo suits.
要不我作为感谢 捐给你们一人一套西装
What if... as a thank you... A donation... I buy you each a suit?
你们好好打扮下 带上妻子共进晚餐
You get all dressed up, you take the wife out for dinner.
像你们工作这么卖力 这都是应得的
I mean... guys like you, you work hard, you deserve it.
他们不应该那样对我
They were wrong for the way they treated me,
而你还给他们钱
and you rewarded them.
我被雇佣来保证让你按时参加演出
I was hired to get you from one show to the next.
我怎么做跟你没关系
How I do it shouldn't matter to you.
- 我希望你没贿赂他们 - 我做了该做的
- I just wish you hadn't paid them off. - I did what I had to do.
这事要是传出去了 你的职业生涯就完了
You know, if this got out it would kill your career.
好了 托尼
OK. Tony.
我不需要你
I need you to stop it with
那套虚假的利他主义 也别来关心我的职业生涯
your phony altruism and concern for my career.
你这话什么意思
What the hell does that mean?
你当时只是在为自己考虑
You were only thinking about yourself back there
因为你知道如果我错过一场演出
because you know if I miss a show,
你的收入也会受到损失
it comes out of your pocket book.
我当然不想让你错过演出
Of course I don't want you to miss a show,
你这个白眼狼
you ungrateful bastard!
你觉得我这么做只为了我自己
You think I'm doing this for my health?
今晚我帮了你大忙 表现出一点感激好吗
Tonight I saved your ass, so show a little appreciation... maybe?
况且 我都跟你说了 没我陪着哪都别去
Besides, I told you never to go nowhere without me!
我觉得你应该不会想陪我去干那种事
I assumed you would want this to be the exception.
孟菲斯
田纳西州
需要我在演出前去弄点化妆品什么的吗
Want me to get some makeup or something before the show?
不 我没事
No I'm fine.
- 你确定吗 瘀伤还挺明显的 - 我说了没事
- You sure? Bruise kindda shrugs. - I said I'm fine.
好的
Okay.
托尼·利普
Tony Lip?
多米尼克 麦格斯 你们在这儿做什么
Dominic, Mags. What the hell you guys doing here?
布鲁克林派我们来的 处理一些事情
Brooklyn sent us down... take care of a few things.
那个黑鬼是谁
我给他工作
怎么了 是打赌输了吗
你到底在做什么
你要工作就来找我 我给你找
况且这周我正需要你帮忙
你可以大赚一笔
一大笔钱
我早就开始赚钱了
我可不信
这里不适合谈论这些
我在这里工作
I am working here.
八点整酒吧见
明白
好的 过会儿见
忘了那个家伙
抱歉医生 他们是我纽约的朋友
Sorry Doc, they are some friends from New York.
- 把谢利医生的行李拿好 - 好的
- Hey, you get Dr Shirley's luggage? - Alright.
给他的房间打电话了 他一会儿就下来
Called his room. He'll be down in a minute.
- 医生 - 你要去哪
- Hey Doc. - Where are you off to?
去楼下 喝几杯
Just going downstairs. To have a drink.
和你朋友 多米尼克
在你接受他的提议之前
我们得谈谈
托尼
Tony...
我认为你做得很出色
I think you're doing a wonderful job.
所以
So...
我想正式给你
I would like to formally
巡回演出经理的职位
offer you the position of my road manager.
有了这个头衔...
With the title...
就有更多的责任
also comes more responsibility but
但薪水也更多
that also means a raise in pay.
不不不 谢了
No. No. No, thanks.
我们说好了的
I mean, we agreed on a
一周125美元 加上花销
hundred and twenty- five a week, plus expenses.
我们说好的 对吧
That's our deal. Right?
我哪儿也不去 医生 就是下去告诉他们
I ain't goin' nowhere, Doc. I was just goin' down to tell 'em.
托尼
Tony...
昨晚的事我很抱歉
I'm sorry about last night.
别挂在心上
Don't worry about it.
我这辈子都在纽约的夜总会工作
I been working nightclubs in the New York city my whole life...
我知道...
I know it's...
这个世界很复杂
complicated world.
你从哪学会弹钢琴的
So, where'd you learn how to play like that?
我妈教的
My mother.
你妈妈 真的吗
Your mother... really?
她用一架旧的小钢琴教我
She taught me how to play in an old spinet.
从我学会走路就开始教
Soon as I could walk.
环游在佛罗里达走廊地区
Travel around the Florida Panhandle...
在教区和礼堂搞个小演出
put on my little shows in parishes and halls...
幸运的是有个人看到了我演奏
Fortunately a man who had seen me play
他安排我在列宁格勒音乐学院学习
arranged for me to study at the Leningrad Conservatory of Music.
我是那里接收的第一个黑人
I was the first Negro ever accepted there.
所以就是在那里 他们教会了你弹奏的曲子
So that's where they taught you all them songs you play?
其实 我是被训练去弹古典音乐
Actually, I was trained to play classical music.
勃拉姆斯 弗朗兹·李斯特 贝多芬 肖邦
Brahms, Franz Liszt, Beethoven, Chopin...
当时我就想弹奏那些
it's all I ever wanted to play.
但我的唱片公司说服了我
But I was persuaded by my record company
然后我去转行从事流行音乐
to pursue a career in popular music instead.
他们坚持认为 观众绝不会接受
They insisted that audiences would never
古典音乐舞台上有一个黑人钢琴家
accept a negro pianist on the classical stage.
想让我变成另一个普通的黑人艺人
Wanted to turn me into just another colored entertainer.
你知道那个
You know the guy who...
弹奏的时候 在钢琴上
smoking while he's playing, sets a glass of whiskey
放着一杯威士忌 然后还抱怨
on his piano and then he complains
因为他没有像亚瑟·鲁宾斯坦一样受人尊重
because he's not respected like Arthur Rubinstein.
亚瑟·鲁宾斯坦可不会
You don't see Arthur Rubenstein
把一杯威士忌放在钢琴上
putting a glass of whiskey on his piano.
我说不好
I don't know...
我觉得你要是坚持
Personally, I think if you stuck to that
往古典音乐方向发展 那会是一个大错
classic stuff it would've been a big mistake.
错误
A mistake?
演奏我训练了一辈子的音乐会是错误
Performing the music I trained my entire life to play?
训练 你把自己当什么了 海豹吗
Trained? What are you, a seal?
大家都爱听你的演奏
People love what you do.
每个人都能弹得像
Anyone can sound like
贝多芬或者肖"帮"或者任何一个你刚刚说的大人物
Beethoven or Joe Pan or them other guys you said.
但你的音乐 你弹奏出来的
But your music, what you do...
只有你能做到
Only you can do that.
谢谢你 托尼
Thank you Tony.
但是 并不是每个人都能弹肖邦的曲子
But... not everyone can play Chopin...
不能像我那样弹
not like I can.
树木脱下了多叶的外衣
The trees have shed their leafy clothing
颜色也褪成灰色和棕色
and their colors have faded to grays and browns.
我看见成千上万颗树
I saw a millions of trees all
被大雪覆盖 犹如童话之境
dusted with snow just like out of a fairy tale.
他描写得好传神
Oh, he's so expressive.
不得不承认 利普的信
Gotta admit, Lip's letters...
- 还不赖 - 毕竟是家族天赋
- They are not bad. - Oh well! It's in the family.
据说我们的曾曾曾祖父
They say our great, great, great grandfather
帮助达芬奇完成西斯廷教堂
helped Da Vinci with the Sistine Chapel.
你说的是米开朗基罗吧
You mean Michelangelo?
对
Right.
米开朗基罗和写信有什么关系
What is Michelangelo have to do with writing letters?
我只是想说 我们是艺术世家
I'm just saying, we're an arty family.
我会数着每一个小时
I would count the hours...
每一分钟 每一秒 直到你在我臂弯里
minutes... and seconds... until you are in my arms.
爱你 托尼
Love you, Tony.
附言 亲亲孩子们
P.S. Kiss the kids.
- 约翰 - 怎么了
- John. - Yeah?
我也想要一封信
I want a letter.
好啊 你做饭我就给你
Yeah, as soon as you make a meal.
小石城
阿肯色州
注意看路
Eyes on the road.
托尼
Tony.
各位 我们用路易斯安那州最热烈的方式欢迎
Alright everybody! Let's give a finest Louisiana
唐·谢利先生和唐·谢利三重奏
welcome to Don Shirley and the Don Shirley Trio!
巴吞鲁日
路易斯安那州
图珀洛
密西西比州
杰克逊
妈的 什么鬼天气
Your mother's ass... piece of shit.
那家伙在做什么
What the hell's this guy doing?
狗娘养的
Son of a bitch.
驾照和通行文件
License and papers?
很高兴见到你
Am I glad to see you.
我们开离了主路 现在迷路了
We had a turn off from main road... and uh, now we're lost.
- 下车 - 我干什么了
- Step out of the car. - What I do?
下车
Out of the car.
你为什么在这路上
Why you on this road?
我跟你说了 我们不得不绕道走 结果迷路了
I told you, we had to make a detour and we got lost.
你为什么载着他
And why you driving him?
他是我老板
He's my boss.
他晚上不允许在这儿 这是日落城
He can't be out here at night. This is a sundown town.
美国南方重建时期
强制实行种族隔离的地区
什么意思
What's that?
让他下车 检查他的身份证
Get him out of the car. Check his I.D.
别这样 现在正下大雨 长官
Come on, it's pouring rain sir.
我可以直接从窗户拿到
I can just get it right here through the window.
让他下车
Get him out of the car!
赶紧的 下车 下车
Come on. Get out now! Get out!
你有身份证吗
You got ID?
怎么读这个姓氏
How you say this last name?
瓦莱隆加
Vallelonga.
这是什么鬼名字
'Hell kind of name is that?
是意大利语
It's Italian.
明白了 所以你才为他开车
Now I see. That's why you driving him around.
你自己也是半个黑鬼
You half a nigger yourself.
手举起来 快点
Hands in the air, now, now!
打扰一下
Excuse me.
打扰一下 警官们
Excuse me, sirs.
我明白为什么我的助理被捕
I understand why my associate is being held,
但我又是犯了什么事呢
but what exactly am I being charged with?
你们看上去都是讲道理的人
You seem like reasonable men.
能放我出来
Perhaps you could let me out
好让我们进一步讨论下现在的情况吗
so that we could discuss the situation further?
别费口舌了 小子
Just put the apple butter away, boy.
你一时半会哪儿都别想去
You ain't goin' nowhere no time soon.
- 你们不能无端关押我 - 我还真有原因
- You cannot hold me without cause! - Well I got cause.
你就不配晚上经过这里
'Cause you let the sun set on your black ass!
我想找我的律师谈话 我要打电话
I want to speak to my lawyer, I want my call!
这是在公然违反我的权利
This is a flagrant violation of my rights!
其实
You know...
他确实有这些权利
He does have... rights.
那就给这黑人打电话 你满意了吧
Give the negro his goddamn phone call. You happy?
你居然还有律师 打吧
You know a lawyer? Call him.
我妈常对我说
As my mother always said,
你真是傻出新境界了
what kind of brand new fool are you?
看看他们
Look at them over there.
好好看看你打的那位警官 看看他
Take a good look at the officer you hit. Look at him.
他在那儿不知道有多惬意
He's over there having a grand old time,
和同事聊着天
chatting up his pals,
喝着热咖啡 而你在哪
enjoying a nice cup of coffee. And where are you?
和无辜的我一起关在这里
In here, with me, who did nothing.
但最后遭殃的人是我
Yet I'm the one who pays the price.
是我会错过明天的伯明翰演出
I'm the one who's gonna miss the Birmingham show.
你要是没去成
Hey, I'm losing a lot of money, too,
我也会损失一大笔钱好吗
if you don't play Birmingham.
你闹的那点脾气 值得吗
So that little temper tantrum... was it worth it?
靠暴力你永远都赢不了 托尼
You never win with violence, Tony,
只有保持了自尊你才能赢
you only win when you maintain your dignity.
自尊总能获胜
Dignity always prevails.
但今晚因为你 我们输得一塌糊涂
And tonight, because of you, we did not.
我要是你就不会碰床垫 医生
I wouldn't touch that mattress, Doc.
不 先生
No, sir.
不 我不是 先生
No. No I'm not, sir.
是的 他就在这里 好的
Yes, sir, he's right here. Yes sir.
- 遵命 - 给我
- Yes sir. - Give me.
我是普拉特警长 你哪位
Chief Pratt... who's this?
糊弄谁呢
Bull- oney.
是 先生
Yes sir.
我能听见 州长先生
I can hear it now, Governor.
没有先生 我很抱歉
No sir, I'm sorry.
我当然能认出您的声音
But, of course I recognize your voice.
先生
Sir...
您是说我们关起来的那小子打给了谁
You saying the boy we got locked up called who?
然后他打给了你
And he called you?
不 先生 但有位警官遭到袭击...
No sir, but an officer was assaulted in the line of...
不 州长先生 我不想
No sir, I don't want no
国民警卫队的人来这 先生
National Guard coming down here, neither, sir.
是 州长先生 我马上就办
Yes, Governor, immediately.
祝您和夫人晚安
Good night to you and the missus.
- 放了他们 - 什么
- Get them out. - What?!
- 赶紧把他们放了 - 那个意大利佬打了我
- Cut 'em goddamn loose. - That dago- wop hit me!
你还想留在这干活吗 那老子说什么
You keep your goddamn job? Then you do what I goddamn
你就按老子说的做
tell you to do, when I goddamn tell you to do it.
现在老子要你把他们给放了
Now I'm telling you to get 'em the goddamn out.
你打电话给谁了
Who the hell did you call?
鲍比·肯尼迪居然救了我们一命
Bobby Kennedy just saved our asses!
天啊 这简直太棒了
Maddon... How great is that?!
棒什么棒
It's not great.
一点都不棒 这是丢人现眼
It's not great at at all, it's humiliating.
你开什么玩笑 我们差点就要完蛋了
'The hell you talking about? We were screwed, now we ain't.
我刚刚让美国的司法部长
And I just put the Attorney General of the United States
- 左右为难 - 那又怎样
- in an incredibly awkward position. - So what?
他赚钱就是干这个的
That's what the guy gets paid for.
难不成他还有什么使命
What else he got to do?
他和他哥哥正在试图改变这个国家
That man and his brother are trying to change this country,
那就是他的使命
that's what else he's got to do!
现在他觉得我成了那种
Now he thinks I'm some kind of...
会在边远沼泽地旁的监狱里打电话
Calling from some backwoods swamp jail,
请他解决袭警罪的人
asking to attenuate assault charges...
谁会做这种事
who does that?
垃圾才会做这种事
Garbage, that's who.
你不应该打那位警官
You shouldn't have hit him.
我不喜欢他当时对你的态度
I didn't like the way he was treating you,
让你那样淋雨
making you stand out in the rain like that.
拜托 你是因为他对你的称呼才动的手
Please, you hit him because of what he called you.
我一辈子都得忍受那种挖苦
I've had to endure that kind of talk my entire life,
你连一个晚上都忍受不了吗
you should be able to take it for at least one night.
就因为我不是黑人
What, I can't get mad at
我就不能因为他说的话生气了吗
that stuff he was saying 'cause I ain't black?
- 老天 我比你更像黑人 - 你说什么
- Christ, I'm blacker than you are. - Excuse me?
你一点都不了解你们种族
You don't know shit about your own people!
吃什么 怎么说话 怎么生活
What they eat, how they talk, how they live.
你都不知道小理查德是谁
You don't even know who Lil' Richard is!
认识小理查德就说明你比我更像黑人了
Oh, so knowing who Little Richard is makes you blacker than me?
托尼 你要是能听听自己说的这些话
Oh Tony, I wish you could hear yourself sometimes
- 就会知道什么时候该闭嘴了 - 放屁
- you wouldn't talk so damn much. - Bullshit.
我是谁我清清楚楚
I know exactly who I am.
我就是一辈子都生活在
I'm the guy who's lived on the
布朗克斯同一个街区的那个家伙
same neighborhood in the Bronx my entire life,
我和我父母兄弟住在一起
with my mother, my father, my brother,
现在还加上了老婆孩子
and now my wife and kids.
这就是我
That's it, that's who I am.
我还是那个
I'm the asshole who has to
每天都要努力打拼才能供养家庭的混蛋
hustle every goddamn day to put food out on table.
而你呢 这位大人物 住在城堡之上
You? Mr. Big Shot? You live on top of a castle
环游世界为有钱人演奏音乐
traveling around the world doing concerts for rich people...
我住在街头 而你却坐在宝座上
I live on the streets, you sit on a throne
没错 我的世界要比你的更像黑人
so yeah, my world is way more blacker than yours!
靠边停车
Pull over.
- 什么 - 靠边停车
- What? - Pull over.
- 我才不停 - 快停车 托尼
- I ain't pulling over! - Stop the car, Tony!
干什么
What?
你要干什么
What are you doing?!
医生
Doc!
医生 你到底想干什么
Doc, what the hell are you doing?
医生 快回车上去
Doc, get back in the car.
我是住在城堡里没错 托尼
Yes, I live in a castle! Tony.
孤身一人
Alone!
那些白人富翁花钱让我给他们弹钢琴
And rich white people pay me to play piano for them,
是想让自己显得有文化
because it makes them feel cultured.
但只要我一下台
But as soon as I step off that stage
我又变回了那个他们不屑一顾的黑鬼
I go right back to being just another nigger to them.
因为那才是他们真正的文化
Because that is their true culture.
而我只能独自承受这种轻蔑
And I suffer that slight alone,
因为我不被自己人所接受
because I'm not accepted by my own people,
因为我跟他们也不是一类人
because I'm not like them either!
如果我不够黑人 也不够白人
So if I'm not black enough, and if I'm not white enough,
或者是不够男人
and if I'm not man enough,
那请你告诉我 托尼
then tell me, Tony,
我是到底是什么人
what am I?!
我困了
I need some sleep.
好
A'right.
我看到下个旅馆就停
I'll stop by the next place
然后偷偷放你进我房间
we see and I'll sneak you into my room.
不 不 我拒绝
No. No. I refuse to stay
住在不欢迎我的旅馆里
in an establishment where I'm not welcome.
那好吧
Yeah. OK.
《黑人司机的绿皮书》
托尼 你一定要走到哪抽到哪吗
Tony, do you have to smoke everywhere?
我不知道你不喜欢这样
I didn't know it would bother you.
你怎么不提前说一声
Should have told me.
你只要把话说出来就行 医生
All you gotta do is say the word, Doc.
你应该知道你人会比信先到家吧
You do realize you'd be home before that letter arrives?
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我想着一路带回家 省点邮票钱
Just thought of bringing it with me. Save on the stamps.
好吧
A'right.
给我吧 托尼 我帮你改
Tony, give it here, I'll fix it.
无意冒犯 医生 我觉得我现在会写了
No offense, Doc, but I think I got the hang of it now.
亲爱的德洛丽丝 有时你让我想起一栋房子
Dear Dolores. Sometimes you remind me of a house.
房里布置着美丽的灯
A house with beautiful lights on it
住在里面的人都很开心幸福
where everyone happy inside.
很好 托尼 你确实会了
Yes, Tony! You got it.
是吗
Yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
医生 谢谢你教我写信
Doc, thanks for helping me with the letters.
- 你真的很会写 - 我很荣幸 托尼
- You're really good at writing them. - My pleasure, Tony.
等你回家了
You know, when you get home,
要不也给你的兄弟写封信
maybe you should write one to your brother?
他要是想联系我 他知道我住哪
He knows where I am if he ever wants to reconnect.
要是我就不愿意等
If... I wouldn't wait.
这世上到处都是
You know... the world's full
害怕主动迈出第一步的孤独之人
of lonely people afraid to make the first move.
我明天再写吧
Yeah, I'll finish this tomorrow.
其实医生 这一路上我一直有件事没想通
You know Doc, something's been eating at me this whole trip.
"奶子堡"太让我失望了
That Tittsburgh was a major disappointment.
我根本没发现有什么区别 你说呢
I didn't notice any difference at all. Did you?
晚安 托尼
Good night, Tony.
阿拉巴马州
伯明翰
圣诞音乐会就在今晚
唐·谢利三重奏
- 早上好 欢迎 - 欢迎 请进
- Good Evening. Welcome. - Welcome. Come on in.
欢迎您 谢利先生
Welcome, Mr Shirley.
我是这儿的主管 格雷厄姆·金德尔
Graham Kindell, I'm the general manager.
见到您很荣幸
It is a pleasure to meet you.
谢谢 金德尔先生
Thank you, Mr. Kindell.
这位是托尼·瓦莱隆加先生
This is Mr. Tony Vallelonga.
- 很高兴见到你  托尼 - 你好
- Nice to meet you, Tony. - How you doing?
把车停在这就行
Let's keep the car right here on
这可是我们的贵宾专区
our guest of honor spot.
- 这边请 先生们 - 好
- Right this way, gentlemen. - Nice.
- 路上还行吧 - 好极了
- How was your drive up? - Oh it's wonderful.
很好 很好
Good to hear, good to hear.
如你们所想
As you can imagine,
我们的圣诞晚会是一年来最盛大的晚会
our Christmas show is the biggest show of the year
我们很高兴能邀请您来 谢利先生
and we are so happy to have you here, Mr Shirley.
如果您有任何需要 一定要告诉我
So, if you need anything... anything t'all... you let me know.
- 谢谢 - 我们到了
- Oh, thank you. - Now, here we are...
离演出还有一小时 有什么疑问吗
I got about an hour before show time. Any questions?
餐厅在哪
Where's the restaurant?
托尼 你就沿着走廊往里走
Well, you continue down the hall here, Tony,
然后右转 穿过大堂就是
to the right, across the lobby.
- 好运 演出顺利 - 谢谢
- Good luck! Break a leg. - Thank you.
他说还有一小时 饿坏了吧 医生
He said we've got an hour. You must be starving, Doc.
你先去 我们到那见
Go ahead, I'll meet you there.
这桌还有人吗
May we join you?
坐吧
Get in.
- 要鸡尾酒吗 先生们 - 我不用了
- Cocktail, gentlemen? - I'm good.
来三杯伏特加
Three shots Vodka.
最后一场演出
Last show.
冷战结束 也该停战了
Cold War over. Time for truce.
- 谢利医生在更衣室吗 - 是啊
- Is Dr. Shirley in his dressing room? - Yeah.
清洁间还差不多
More like a broom closet.
老实说 我想不通他怎么遭得住这种对待
Tell you, I don't know why he puts up with that shit.
六年前 在1956年
Six years ago, in 1956,
纳·京·科尔受邀到
Nat King Cole was invited to perform
伯明翰的市政大礼堂演出
at the Municipal Auditorium here in Birmingham.
科尔先生是首位受邀的黑人
Mr. Cole was the first negro
在这座城里的白人场所演出
asked to play at a white establishment in this city.
但他刚开始表演 就有一群人非难他
As soon as he started playing, a group of men attacked him
说他在表演白人的音乐
for playing white people's music.
然后把他拉下了台
They pulled him off stage
狠揍了一顿
beat him badly.
我的天啊
Jesus Christ!
你之前问过我
You asked me once,
为什么谢利医生要做这些演出
why Dr. Shirley does this?
我告诉你
I tell you.
那是因为天才还远远不够
Because genius is not enough.
要想改变人心 需要的是勇气
It takes courage to change people's hearts.
谢谢
Thanks.
Thank you.
- 晚上好 - 需要帮忙吗
- Good evening. - Can I help you?
- 我理解 但是... - 怎么了
- I understand but... - What's going on?
这位先生说我不能在这里用餐
This gentleman says that I'm not permitted dine here.
不 你不知道
No, you don't understand,
他是今晚的演奏者 重头戏
he's playing tonight, he's the main event.
很抱歉 但这是餐厅的规矩
I'm sorry. But it's the policy of the restaurant.
- 一切都还好吗 - 不 不好
- Everything all right? - No, it's not all right.
这个家伙说谢利医生不能在这里用餐
This guy is saying Dr. Shirley can't eat here.
我向您道歉 但这是餐厅悠久的传统
Well, I apologize, but these are... longstanding traditions.
俱乐部规矩 我相信您一定理解
Club rules. I'm sure you understand.
不 我不理解
No. I do not understand.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
等等 你是说他乐队里的陪衬
Wait a minute, are you tellin' me the bozos in his band,
和专程到此听他演奏的人们
and these people that came here to see him play,
他们能在这里用餐
they can eat here,
但演出者 今晚荣誉嘉宾却不能
but the star of the show, the talking spot of honor, he can't.
恐怕是这样
I'm afraid not.
但他总得吃饭 总得吃晚餐
Well he's gotta eat, I mean he's gotta have dinner.
这样吧
I tell you what.
不如我们送些食物到他的更衣室
Why don't we bring something to his dressing room, huh?
约翰 把菜单给这位先生
John, show him the menu.
不 我拒绝在储藏室用餐
No. I'm not eating in that storage room.
好吧 如果您愿意
Okay... if you'd prefer,
这条路上有一家很不错的餐馆
there's a very popular establishment right down the road,
橙鸟酒吧 他们肯定愿意接待您
the Orange Bird, they'd be happy to feed you.
医生 借一步说话
Doc, come here.
稍等
One second just.
也许那地方更好呢
C'mon, maybe that place is better anyway.
这里的餐包硬得像石头一样
The dinner rolls here are like rocks.
我们就去那吃饭 速去速回
Let's just go over... just go and come back.
这是最后一场演出了
It's the last show.
咱们善始善终 熬过今晚
Bottom of the knife. Let's just get it over with
就能回家 并远离这群混蛋
and we can go home and get away from these pricks.
这是菜单 今晚的鱼非常新鲜
Ah, there you go, the fish is wonderful tonight.
除非让我在这里用餐 否则今晚就没有演出
Either I eat in this room, or I'm not performing tonight.
我能和你谈谈吗
May I have a word with you?
维兰纽瓦先生 麻烦你和谢利先生讲讲理
Mr. Villanueva, you have to talk sense to Mr. Shirley.
让你理解我们不是针对他个人
Please make him understand we're not insulting him personally,
这只是这里的办事方法
this is just the way things are done down here.
好吧 但他不是这里的人
Yeah, well he's not from down here.
你就让他别这么固执
Just ask him to be reasonable.
我这里有四百位客人等着看今晚的演出
I got 400 guests in there who expect to be entertained tonight.
谢利医生希望在这里用餐
And Dr. Shirley expects to eat tonight.
为什么你不能破一次例呢
Why can't you just make an exception this one time?
我跟你讲个故事
Lemme tell you a story.
你听说过波士顿凯尔特人篮球俱乐部吗
You ever hear of the Boston Celtics basketball club?
- 听说过 - 那些男孩两年前
- Yeah. - Yeah, those boys came through here
巡回比赛时来过这里
a couple years ago on a barnstorming tour.
看在他们是联赛世界冠军的份儿上
Now, seeing as they were World Champions of the league and all,
我们很兴奋能让他们在这里用餐
we were tickled to have 'em eat here,
我们热烈地欢迎了他们
we rolled out the welcome wagon.
你知道那天晚上他们是在哪张桌子上吃的晚餐吗
So do you know what table their big coon ate at that night?
- 不知道 - 我也不知道
- No. - I don't either.
但反正不是我们的桌子 废话少说
But it wasn't one of ours. Now let's cut the bullshit.
开个价吧
Tell me what it's gonna take.
一百元够不够你说服那小子演出
Say one hundred dollars and you get your boy to play?
你觉得能买通我
You think you can buy me?
无意冒犯 先生
With all due respect, sir,
但你如果不能被买通 也坐不到现在的位置
but you wouldn't be in a job like this if you couldn't be bought.
别这样 托尼
Stop! Tony.
没关系
It's alright.
如果你希望
I'll play.
我就照常演出
If you want me to.
好吧
All right.
我们赶紧离开这鬼地方
Let's get the fuck outta here.
什么意思 离开这里
What do you mean, let's get outta here?
你觉得自己在干什么
Where the hell do you think you're going?
唐 别这样 你签了合同
Don, don't do this! Now you signed a contract.
我知道你是那种遵守信用的人
And I know you're the kind of man who honors a contract!
康妮 比尔 一切都好起来 没关系
Connie, Bill, everything's gonna be fine. It's alright.
你还有场演出呢 先生
You got a show to do, mister!
赶紧回来 现在就回来 该死的 现在
You turn yourself around. Right now goddammit! Right now!
这就是为什么我们不雇黑人的原因
This is why you people don't work down here,
你们根本靠不住
cause you're unreliable.
听见了吗
You hear me?
我特地为你从亚特兰大运来一架斯坦威钢琴
I shipped that goddamn Steinway in from Atlanta for you.
托尼
Tony.
你饿吗
Are you hungry?
这不是废话吗
Does Betty like butter?
橙鸟酒吧
蓝调演出
- 你是警察 - 我看起来像爱尔兰人吗
- You a cop? - Do I look Irish?
你想来点什么 宝贝
What you want, baby?
- 两杯威士忌 不加水 - 马上来
- Two Cutty sarks, neat. - Coming up.
来两份你们的特色菜 是什么都行
Whatever your specialty is, we'll take it.
两份橙鸟套餐
Two orange birds!
我欣赏你在那的做法 医生
I like what you did back there, Doc.
你维护了自己的权利
You stood up for yourself.
就像你的总统好友说的
It's like your friend the President says:
约翰·肯尼迪就职演讲
正确版本为"问你能为国家做点什么"
"不要问你的国家能为你做什么
"Ask notyour country what you could do for it,
问你能为你自己做点什么"
ask what you do for yourself."
你懂的
You know.
亲爱的
So, darlin',
你穿得这么体面是要干什么
what you do, all dressed up like that?
没什么特别重要的事
Nothing particularly important.
不能以貌取人
Shouldn't judge a man by his clothes.
他不过是世界上最厉害的钢琴家罢了
He's only the greatest piano player in the world.
是吗 你弹得好吗
That right? You good?
别害羞 医生 告诉她你是谁
Don't be shy, Doc. Tell her who you are.
不用说 去弹吧
Don't tell me nothing, show me.
老兄
Man...
这才是活跃气氛的正确方式
That's how you break a peak.
那会儿真是好日子啊 我每个月免费弹奏一回
Oh, that was a good time, I do that once a month for free.
- 你真是不可思议 - 托尼
- You're unbelievable. - Hey, Tony.
我打赌如果我们现在出发 能赶得上
I bet if we leave right now, we can make it.
- 赶上什么 - 平安夜 回纽约
- Make what? - Christmas Eve. In New York city.
千万别在酒吧里晃悠一大笔现金
Don't ever flash a wad of cash in a bar.
我就知道你有枪
I knew you had a gun!
雪越来越大了 医生
It's getting bad, Doc.
是的
Yes.
真可惜我们没有
It's a shame we don't
能保护我们一路平安的东西
have something to protect us on our journey.
我想到了 不如你把
Oh I know, why don't you
你的幸运石头放在前板上吧 托尼
put your lucky rock up on the dash, Tony?
拜托 托尼 我们需要动用所有资源
C'mon Tony, we need all the help we can get.
谢谢 我已经感觉安全多了
Thank you. I feel safer already.
你是个混蛋 你知道吗
You're a prick, you know that?
该死
Ah, shit!
天杀的警察
Goddamn cops.
- 你们在这干什么 - 我们想开车去纽约
- What are you doing out here? - We're trying to get to New York.
- 有什么问题吗 警官 - 是的
- Is there a problem, Officer? - Yeah.
我发现你们的车往左倾斜
I noticed your car was tilting to the left.
看上去后胎爆胎了
Looks like your back tire's flat.
接着开 接着开
Keep it moving, keep it moving.
好了 注意安全先生们
OK. Be careful gentlemen.
- 圣诞快乐 - 圣诞快乐 谢谢警官
- Merry Christmas! - Merry Christmas! Thanks officer.
天气预报提醒各位这个平安夜
Weather advisory warning this Christmas Eve,
由于强暴风雪侵袭东部沿海城市
as a major snowstorm is hitting the eastern seaboard
宾夕法尼亚州东部 新泽西州北部
with the severest weather in eastern Pennsylvania,
和纽约的五个行政区将经历最为严峻的天气
northern New Jersey and the five boroughs.
建议出行的各位不要选择收费公路
Travelers are advised to stay off the Jersey Turnpike...
好了 就到这吧 我不开了
A'right. That's it. We're done.
下一个汽车旅馆我们就住下
I'm pulling us into the next motel.
开到你不能开为止 托尼
Keep going as long as you can go Tony.
我都睁不开眼了
I can't keep my eyes open.
脑子要被催眠了
I'm getting hypnotized here.
我感觉自己的脑袋要爆炸了
I think my brain's gonna explode.
我们尝试过了 医生
Hey... we gave it a shot, Doc.
你打算怎么办
What you gonna do?
好了 餐具都摆好了 女士们先生们
Alright, the table is set, ladies and gentlemen.
不准在屋里跑
Don't run in the house.
托尼 托尼 醒醒
Tony. Tony, wake up.
- 你还好吗 - 到你家了 进屋吧
- You alright? - You're home, get inside.
晚安
Goodnight.
等等 一起进来吧 见见我家人
Wait, wait, come up, meet my family...?
圣诞快乐 托尼
Merry Christmas, Tony.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas!
瞧瞧是谁 大文豪回来了
Look who it is, Shakespeare's home!
爸
Dad.
你们好吗
How are you?
我赶上了
I made it back!
托尼 上帝祝福你
Tony, God bless you!
- 你饿了吗 - 饿疯了
- You hungry? - I'm starving.
还有剩什么吗
Anything left?
- 欢迎回家 谢利医生 - 谢谢 阿米特
- Welcome home, Dr. Shirley. - Thank you, Amit.
我已经帮您铺好床了 先生 现在需要打开行李吗
I turned down your bed, sir. Shall I unpack your luggage now?
不用麻烦了 回去陪家人吧
No, no, please. Go home to your family.
谢谢您 先生
Thank you, sir.
- 圣诞快乐 先生 - 圣诞快乐
- Merry Christmas, Sir. - Merry Christmas!
- 拜托 你从没那样亲过我 - 为什么你不那样亲我
- Come on. You never kissed me like that. - Why don't you ever kiss me like that?
行了 放松
A'right, relax.
托尼 你还好吗 今晚有点安静啊
So Tony, you alright? You seem a little quite.
嗯 没事 只是累了
Yeah, nah, I'm just tired.
长途跋涉
Long trip.
那个东西搞定了吗
You take care of that thing?
- 谢了 - 不客气 一共七十五块
- Thanks. - Yeah, you owe me 75 bucks.
七十五 查理说是六十块
Seventy five? Charlie said sixty.
我是免费劳工吗
I'm doing this for free?
托尼 跟我们说说你的旅行 你都走了两个月
Hey, Tony, tell us about the trip. You've been gone for 2 months.
是啊 他人怎么样 那个黑鬼 他惹你生气了吗
Yeah. So how was he, the tutsoon? He get on your nerves?
别这么喊他
Don't call him that.
行
Alright.
托尼 你真该看看上周小弗朗基
Tony, you should have seen the day last week when little Frankie
爬到电视机上的样子 我拍了照 太可爱了
climbed upon the TV. I took a picture of him. He was so cute.
他在电视上特别好笑
He was so funny up there.
你疯了吗 小德
What are you nuts, Dee?
那后面那么多管子 他可能触电
With all the tubes back there, he could've got electrocuted!
又不是面包机 电视机怎么会触电
It's not a toaster. You can't get electrocuted from a TV set.
我又没说面包机 我说的是电视机
I said nothing about the toaster. I'm saying it's a TV.
- 查理 - 利普 约翰尼邀请了我
- Charlie? - Hey Lip. Johnny invited me.
- 那好 请进吧 - 你还记得玛丽吗
- Well, come on in. - You remember Marie?
你好 玛丽
Hey, Marie!
查理 你真的来了 我只是随口一说
Charlie, you actually came? I was kidding?
还带了你妻子
With the wife too?
- 圣诞快乐 - 圣诞快乐 真没想到啊
- Merry Christmas. - Merry Christmas, hello! What a surprise!
很高兴见到你
Nice to see you.
各位 这是当铺的查理
Everybody. Charlie from the pawn shop!
医生
Doc!
欢迎
Welcome!
- 各位 - 别说了 别说了
- Hey, everybody... - Stop it, stop it.
这位是唐纳德·谢利医生
This is Dr Donald Shirley.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
赶紧的 腾个地方 给这位先生拿盘吃的
Well, come on, make some room! Get the man a plate!
- 你好 - 你肯定是德洛丽丝
- Hello! - You must be Dolores.
- 欢迎 - 圣诞快乐
- Welcome! - Buon Natale.
谢谢你和我分享你的丈夫
Thank you for sharing your husband with me.
谢谢你帮他写信
Thank you for helping him with the letters.